<record>
 <name>
  Ben Schulz
 </name>
 <position>
  Project Management Lead
 </position>
 <education>
  Utah State University
  BS
  Information Systems
 </education>
 <bio>
  Ben possesses over 20 years worth of work experience in the development, customization and implementation of construction industry project and program management applications. This, paired with his knowledge of cost engineering, schedule management, and project risk management controls has enabled him to perform project management and estimating services in numerous industries.

He has experiences working as Project Manager, Implementation Specialist, as Data Analyst with P6, Contract Management, and BI Publishing and other report designing software. Ben is a Documentation Specialist experienced in the direct development of several user guides and training manuals. He has been the Technical Project Manager for Oracle Primavera P6 16.2 and Contract Management CM13/CM14 Upgrades for one of our key clients. He is experienced and knowledgeable in business analysis and the development of user requirements. He is also experienced with the Software Development Life Cycle Model. He has personal experience with CM14, Business Intelligence Publisher and with Primavera Contract Manager databases.

He is currently assigned as a Report Writer for Toll's work at the NYC School Construction Authority's PPM Upgrade project. There, he is diligently rewriting and updating Primavera Contract Management reports which are heavily utilized by the project management group. Ben possesses a keen awareness of process and procedure and is meticulous in providing users with desired automation in achieving their business objectives.


 </bio>
 <certificate>
  Project Management Institute
  Project Management Professional
  
 </certificate>
 <image>
  Ben.jpg
 </image>
 <expertise>
  Construction Management
  Contract Books Automation
  Contract Management
  Law Review Integration
  CPM based Scheduling
 </expertise>
 <skills>
  Oracle Primavera P6, CM
  Microsoft Office
  Microsoft Project
  MySQL
 </skills>
 <work>
  Senior Consultant
  Toll International
  June
  2016
  Present
  
  Designs data visualization and a contract book automation system to assist in the delivery of capital construction programs for NYDDC
  Upgraded reporting automation in the SCA's Primavera Contract Manager
  
  Implementation Manager
  Chicago Public Schools
  March
  2014
  June
  2016
  Established Primavera Contract Manager construction documentation system for Chicago Public Schools
  Developed CM custom documents and procedures to automate project practices developed by CPS
  Developed WBS cost coding structure within project
  Designed procedures for change management, tracking & invoicing
  Automated reports for integration of agency policies and procedures into engineering contracts
  
  Implementation Consultant
  Burn & McDonnell
  October
  2000
  October
  2014
  Established a project's Primavera Contract Manager construction documentation system
  Developed a unique costing structure in CM to track costs instantaneously and on-demand
  Developed WBS cost coding structure within the project
  Designed procedures for change management, tracking and invoicing, environmental reporting, real estate location, tracking, purchasing, reselling
  Established specific logs to track key issues including crew tracking, public relations, and local/regional permitting
  Prepared monthly auditing reports
  
  Consultant
  Peak Construction Co.
  January
  2008
  July
  2010
  Responsible for implementation and design of Primavera Contract Manager software
  Created custom forms and reports in Infomaker and trained the users on how to use the tool
  
 </work>
</record>
<record>
 <name>
  Abhishek Singh Banyal
 </name>
 <position>
  Project Controls Specialist
 </position>
 <education>
  New Jersey Institute of Technology
  MSc
  Construction Management
 </education>
 <bio>
  Abhishek Banyal is among Toll International LLC's key Project Controls Specialists and is one of their most promising candidate for this proposal. Abhishek Graduated from SRM University in 2014 and committed to Site-Based work for a Government Contractor for a period of two years before moving to the United States in 2016. He went on to complete his Graduate Degree in Construction Management from the New Jersey Institute of Technology in 2018; and as the best outgoing candidate, was awarded an Institutional Fellowship sponsored by a well-known Civil Engineering firm based in Morristown, NJ for his academic excellence.

Abhishek Banyal possesses an overall work experience of over 3 years and has accumulated a significant amount of site-based field-work during that time. He has been part of heavy engineering and infrastructure construction projects ranging from Hydro-Electric Power Generation in the Utilities Sector, to Roadways and Urban-Rail/Public-mass-transit enterprises in the transportation sector. His notable work experiences have placed him on both sides of the business, having worked in client/consulting as well as contracting agencies. His professional commitments have also netted him an assignment on an International, high-profile project based in the Asian market where he coordinated with professionals from India, England, South Korea, Taiwan and France.

Abhishek Banyal's particular expertise comes from his prior work experiences in maintaining Documentation, Proposal Writing, Contract Management, Estimating with CSI Master Format Specifications, Work-Breakdown-Structuring, Activity Timing / Logic, Activity Scheduling, Resource Allocation / Management, and Earned Value Analysis. His skills cover advanced knowledge of Microsoft Project Professional, and Oracle Primavera P6. Abhishek is also skilled in Autodesk software, having been an Autodesk Inc. endorsed, officially Licensed and web-published Professional since 2012.


 </bio>
 <certificate>
  Constr. Mgmt. Assoc. of America
  Construction Managemer In Training
  
 </certificate>
 <image>
  Abhishek.jpeg
 </image>
 <expertise>
  CPM Scheduling
  Uniformat Estimating
  CAD
  CAE
 </expertise>
 <skills>
  Primavera P6
  ANSYS
  Revit
  AutoCAD
  STAAD.Pro
  Project Professional
  HCS
  ETABS
  SAP 2000
 </skills>
 <work>
  Project Controls Specialist
  Toll International LLC
  April
  2019
  Present
  
  Responsible for the company's outgoing proposals in response to published Requests for Proposals (RFPs) from the Port Authority of New York and New Jersey (PANYNJ)
  Represent the company, in maintenance of outward relations and interactions with partnering subcontractors as well as new prospects
  
  NJIT Fellow; Graduate Engineer
  Louis Berger Inc.
  June
  2018
  August
  2018
  Awarded the 2018 NJIT fellowship sponsored by the Berger charitable foundation
  Contributed to Project Monitoring by Inspection and Data Collection during blasting, mass-excavation, and tunnel boring operations on the Government of Maharashtra, Mumbai Metro Rail Corporation's Underground Line-3 Project
  Reviewed Schedules, Two-week-rolling Programs, Contractor Method Statements, Structural Engineering Drawings, Geo-technical Investigation Reports, Mechanical Engineering Drawings, Crane Load Charts and Data Records
  Witnessed the complete assembly, and Initial-drive of Surya-I -- a dual mode Tunnel Boring Machine procured from Robbins of Solon, Ohio; one of 17 overall TBMs committed to the project
  
  Site Engineer
  M/S Nirmal Rana
  March
  2012
  March
  2015
  On-site technical supervision, assistance & overall quality assurance with respect to roadwork and associated support structures such as drainage culverts, and retaining walls
  
  Engineering Intern
  Public Works Department
  June
  2013
  July
  2013
  Reviewed the design of an RCC bridge, manual and computer aided drafting as well as rain-waterharvesting regulations & practice in the state of Himachal Pradesh, India
  
  Engineering Intern
  National Hydroelectric Power Corporation
  May
  2004
  February
  2006
  Witnessed the execution and production phase of the NHPC's 520 MW, Parbati Hydroelectric Project - III
  With the bulk of the rock-fill type embankment dam, h/t race-tunnels, and powerhouse cavern nearing completion at the time, was introduced to tunnel-boring operations in fractured rock, underground construction, and the typical developmental progression of hydroelectric power projects
  
 </work>
</record>
<record>
 <name>
  Samir Rafla
 </name>
 <position>
  Senior Scheduler 
 </position>
 <education>
  Minya University
  BS
  Civil Engineering
 </education>
 <bio>
  Samir Rafla has held 16 years of continuous professional experience in the construction industry, implementing the most current Project Scheduling and Project Controls techniques for projects in a number of business sectors. With his scheduling skills and planning acumen, Samir has often been a part of high-performance teams striving to achieve excellence in the optimal balance between efficiency and quality of accomplished work. Through his years of work experiences and the soundness of his ability, Samir brings an appreciable repertoire of both technical as well as soft-skills and communicating ability to this proposal.

Samir Rafla has developed a deep understanding of project performance indicators, as well as strong analytical and problem-solving skills, which have allowed him to consistently achieve a proven track record in the field of Project Scheduling and Planning. During the course of his notable experiences, Samir has also had the particular experience of using forensic techniques for claims analysis.

The most noteworthy of Samir's experiences include his scheduling-associated work contributions on an aviation project for an International Airport in Africa. He was also involved in a similar capacity for work on the flagship Grand Museum in Egypt. He currently serves the MTA's NYCT, on their Brooklyn Expressway PS-281 project on his current assignment with Toll International LLC. 

Samir's particular specialties include Oracle Primavera P6 Contract Management, Risk Analysis, Project Controls Techniques, Project Resource Management, Budgeting, Financial Control, Forensic Claims Analyses, Feasibility Studies, Bidding, Evidence Law, Sources / Regimes of Obligation as well as Delay related claims & disputes in the construction industry.
 </bio>
 <certificate>
  Project Management Institute
  Planning Scheduling Professional
  
  Project Management Institute
  Project Management Professional
  
 </certificate>
 <image>
  Samir.jpeg
 </image>
 <expertise>
  Project Planning & Control
  Resource Management
  FDIC Contracting
  Feasibility Studies
  Forensic Claims Analysis
  Systems Design & Architecture
 </expertise>
 <skills>
  Oracle Primavera P6
  Microsoft Project Professional
  Microsoft Office
  Sage Estimating(Sage 100 & 300)
 </skills>
 <work>
  Senior Scheduler
  Toll Internationall LLC
  January
  2019
  Present
  
  Develops construction schedules for MTA-NYCT Design/Build projects
  Assists PM towards achieving control over the project aspects of time, cost, and earned value
  Provides forensic claims analysis
  Provides Schedule updates with the associated narrative
  Manages planning issues with the project team and other stakeholders.
  Provides substantiation and particulars to the Contractor’s planning submissions
  Establishes monthly reporting procedures and updates to client and senior management
  Prepares weekly and monthly reports for team and senior management
  
  Planning & Forensic Claims Manager
  BAM International
  March
  2015
  Januart
  2019
  Provided management assistance to the PM with respect to PMI standards
  Generated Master Schedule and provided periodic revisions
  Led planning team for the delivery of the key and other required tasks 
  Provided schedule progress, KPI's and earned value updates
  Performed Risk analyses using Monte Carlo Simulations
  Managed issues with subcontractors
  Developed forensic planning and claims analyses
  
  Deputy Planning Manager
  Besix - Orascom
  March
  2012
  March
  2015
  Generated Master Schedule and provided periodic revisions
  Managed schedule timeline and resolved all planning related issues
  Developed linear scheduling for resource utilization
  Generated Forensic Planning and Claims Analyses for the project
  Established key deliverable milestones in coordination with upper management
  Provided forecasting (personnel, material, funds) for the project lifetime
  Provided forensic planning related assistance to DAB Members
  
  Senior Planning Engineer
  Orascom - Hassan Allam
  November
  2007
  February
  2012
  Assisted with preparation, management, and overview of strategic planning
  Assisted with design, procurement, and construction schedules for the project
  Reviewed scheduling trends to identify potential problems & corrective action
  
  Planning Engineer
  Orascom Construction Industries
  May
  2004
  February
  2006
  Prepared construction schedules and provided periodic progress updates
  Reviewed invoices and prepared comparison sheets for final review
  Calculated productivity rates
  
 </work>
</record>
