<record>
 <name>
  Martin Tokarczyk
 </name>
 <position>
  Cost Estimator
 </position>
 <education>
  University of Calgary
  BS
  Civil Engineering
  
 </education>
 <bio>
  Martin is an experienced cost estimator with Experienced Cost Estimator and Project Manager with a demonstrated history of working in both the cost estimating and scheduling industries. Skilled in Oracle Primavera and CMSI, Project Management, and Construction Management. Background in Civil Engineering where h holds a Bachelor of Civil Engineering with Distinction from the University of Calgary. Value-oriented certified cost professional and certified estimating professional with over 12 years of experience in estimating and project management on capital projects; construction and energy. Detail-oriented with the capacity to identify and resolve issues and impediments to success. Excellent interpersonal and communication skills with the aptitude to work collaboratively within a team-oriented environment.

Martin believes he has a penchant for being able to 'build the project in his mind” and to have all necessary know-how to account for all factors which may not be typically considered in the early stages of project development. Martin is very pro-active in terms of acclimating to the most current and industry-standard software and is capable of quickly getting up to speed with any new software environments as and whenever required by his specific task assignments.


 </bio>
 <certificate>
  American Association of Cost Engineers
  Certified Cost Professional
  
  American Association of Cost Engineers
  Certified Estimating Professional
  
 </certificate>
 <image>
  MartinTokarczyk.jpg
 </image>
 <expertise>
  Project Management
  Estimating
  Project Controls
 </expertise>
 <skills>
  Oracle Primaver P6
  Microsoft Office
  CMSi
  SAP cost module
 </skills>
 <work>
  Consultant
  Tokar Consulting Inc.
  January
  2007
  Present
  
  Developed parametric estimates, project estimates, forecasting and verification estimates
  Estimated cost on pipeline construction programs and projects (key member of Project Management Team)
  Listed key scope covered by the cost estimate and identified scope not covered by the estimate
  Developed class 3 estimates for budgetary control and project authorization
  Evaluated contractor’s cost estimating process to ensure that the estimate covered the entire scope of the project and that it met the class 3 deliverable accuracy
  Interacted closely with vendors, stakeholders, other engineers and contractors
  Collaborated with other engineers and project managers to predict the estimate at completion
  Reconciled and managed cost variances, milestone payments, bank balances, invoices
  Archived historical estimating data such as schedule, cost, quantity, for future use
  Established cost forecasts utilizing actual cost data, earned value and productivity
  Evaluated and reviewed weekly construction progress reports: scope, schedule and cost
  Supported the team as required to reach a final investment decision
  
  Project Analyst
  Encana
  October
  2008
  Januart
  2009
  Normalized contract rates with General Contractors
  Estimated construction programs and projects; identified entire scope of the estimate
  Created and approved Work Breakdown Structure (WBS)
  Managed Master Service Agreements, Purchase Orders and Change Order Requisitions
  
  Contract Coordinator
  Colt Engineering
  March
  2006
  October
  2008
  Managed construction service contracts and the corresponding project forecasts and estimates. Scope: pipelines, facilities, chemical processing plants, electrical and instrumentation, camp facilities, equipment rental, hot tap services, survey services, road construction, scaffolding purchase and rental, construction supervision, delivery services.
  
 </work>
</record>
<record>
 <name>
  Amir Mortazavi
 </name>
 <position>
  Project Manager
 </position>
 <education>
  Julius Maximilians University
  MBA
  Business Integration
  
  University of California Davis
  BS
  Electrical Engineering
  
 </education>
 <bio>
  Amir Mortazavi is a seasoned Project Engineer with more than 14 years of International experiences in the development of residential construction based as well as more industrially oriented projects. Amir was formally educated first in the engineering disciplines at the University of California, Davis; before moving to Wurzburg, Germany for a Business degree. During the course of his career, Amir Mortazavi has represented and interfaced directly with several international construction companies on large-scale and complex projects with very cost loaded budgets and tight schedules.

Amir Mortazavi has notable skills in strategic planning, budgeting, vendor management, project engineering, team building, and documentation. His residential construction experience also includes pre-fabrication techniques. Notwithstanding, Amir Mortazavi has the unique distinction of having performed his services during times of international conflict within Iraq, where he was also involved on water resource, and petrochemical industry related projects.

There is not a sliver of remaining doubt in the collective opinion of our company that Amir Mortazavi's strength of character and demonstrated history of professional excellence would not be a most precious addition to the project management team for this project. It is with great pleasure that Toll International proposes Amir as one of the leading Project Engineering candidates for this proposal.


 </bio>
 <certificate>
  Project Management Institute
  Project Management Professional
  
 </certificate>
 <image>
  Amir.jpg
 </image>
 <expertise>
  Critical Path Method Scheduling
  Construction Planning
  Value Engineering
  Cost Management
  Contract Management
 </expertise>
 <skills>
  Oracle Primavera P6, CM
  Microsoft Project Professional
  Autodesk AutoCAD
  Sage Estimating (Timberline)
 </skills>
 <work>
  Lead Scheduler
  Toll International LLC
  April
  2019
  Present
  
  Serves as lead scheduler for the delivery of Engineering, and Project / Program Management Services
  
  Consulting Project Manager
  Productif
  February
  2019
  April
  2019
  Design and implementation of a modular, pre-fabrication & renewable energy based manufacturing system for construction applications
  Defined project scope and procedures
  Planned, monitored, and controlled, the project schedule
  
  Sr. Project Manager
  Farabeton Construction Co.
  March
  2007
  August
  2018
  Managed over 100 subcontractors and from pre-construction thru final handover to 2000 end-users on a 71 story apartment complex project
  Planned, monitored, controlled, and delivered the project under budget and on schedule
  Managed the project supply-chain through international sanctions and domestic yearly inflation of 70% with minimum effect on project budget and schedule
  Planned and managed all the legal and operational requirements on a prior turn-key construction of 50 residential buildings
  Conducted bids, selected, and managed the project subcontractors
  Planned, managed, and monitor the project budget, scope, and schedule thru 25% completion
  Successfully closed out the project without any pending financial or legal obligations when the project was canceled by the client due to war and instability of the region
  
 </work>
</record>
<record>
 <name>
  Michael Cholden-Brown
 </name>
 <position>
  Project Manager
 </position>
 <education>
  Columbia University
  MS
  Civil Engineering
  
  University of Cal. Berkeley
  BS
  Civil Engineering
  
 </education>
 <bio>
  Micheal is an Experienced Construction and Project Controls Manager with Extensive Project Controls Management, Cost, Schedule, and Strategic Analysis expertise. Experienced in Program Planning and Management, Cost and Risk Management, Resource Budgeting, and Organizational Realignment and Optimization. Over 25 years of experience with Primavera systems. He has worked on Bayonne Bridge “Raise the Roadway” project in Staten Island, MTA East Side Access Transit Program ($10.9 B), the $3.5B Croton Water Treatment Plant, $400M CAD EPCM Ore Mining Project in Quebec and many more state-level projects.

Micheal went to two very prestigious schools, the University of California Berkley where he received his Bachelor's in Science in Civil Engineering and Columbia University where he received his Masters in Science for Civil Engineering as well. He has developed multiple software skills such as Oracle Primavera P6, Contract Manager, Microsoft Office, and AutoCAD.


 </bio>
 <certificate>
  Project Management Institute
  Project Management Professional
  
  American Association of Cost Engineers
  Certified Cost Professional
  
  American Association of Cost Engineers
  Planning Scheduling Professional
  
 </certificate>
 <image>
  MichaelCholden.jpg
 </image>
 <expertise>
  Heavy Industrial Construction
  Chemical Plants
  Oil Refineries
  Project Management
 </expertise>
 <skills>
  Oracle Primavera P6, CM
  Microsoft Office
  Autodesk AutoCAD
 </skills>
 <work>
  Senior Project Manager
  MBP Consulting Engineers
  January
  2016
  Present
  
  Submitted a claim for Structural Steel impacts of greater than $400M that must be analyzed and defense for the Port Authority provided.
  Working on improvement in the configuration and use of the e-Builder Project Management System by the CM staff.
  Developing claim analysis for Bayonne Bridge and other projects handled by the firm.
  
  Senior Cost Engineer
  Macdonald- Bedford
  October
  2012
  June
  2016
  Performed Cost and Budget Controls and Risk Informed Forecasting on Federal Transit Administration (FTA) construction program.
  Performed full budget, estimate, and cost projections and reviews.
  Ensured Compliance with Project Execution, Management, Cost and Schedule Management Plans.
  Used Earned Value, Trending, and Risk Assessment methodologies and produces independent Cost Control reviews and reports.
  Oversaw Metropolitan Transit Authority use of Project Controls best practices.
  
  Scheduling Manager
  Malcom Pirnie
  January
  2012
  October
  2012
  Provided Scheduling and Claims review, analysis and defense, and was responsible for the Risk Assessment and Management program.
  Reviewed Project’s Integrated Master Schedule (>35,000 activities) created and maintained in P3, and utilized P6 through Citrix for analysis.
  Developed monthly Schedule Analysis Reports and gave monthly presentations to DEP on ‘Issues & Tasks’.
  
  Project Controls Manager
  AECOM
  July
  2009
  December
  2011
  Served as Lead Schedule Analyst/Manager for NYC Water Programs on CM and Design Services projects.
  Managed the Primavera Expedition/Contract Manager, Constructware, and P3/P6 systems.
  Controlled CM schedules in P3, Program schedules in P6, and Design schedules iin MS Project.
  Produced monthly analytic reports on performance and on process improvement, provided claims analysis and defense, and testified on NYC Controller Audits.
  Provided financial and trending analyses, forecasts, and performance/ productivity metrics.
  
 </work>
</record>
<record>
 <name>
  Maqsood Ahmed
 </name>
 <position>
  Associate Operations Analyst
 </position>
 <education>
  Manhattan College
  BS
  Civil Engineering
  
 </education>
 <bio>
  Mr. Ahmed is an associate operational analysis Specialist with over five years of industry experience as a highly competent, motivated and result oriented project analyst, cost engineer and information technology specialist. He provides Project Control Services and site management services for a variety of new construction and refurbishing projects in the tristate area. Mr. Ahmed?s diversified work experience reflects his ability to interface effectively and efficiently with all levels of management, engineers, contractors, and teammates, and the distinct situations that involve them. He is motivated, self-starting, and goal-oriented with proven abilities in assisting the project managers and clients with project controls tasks. In addition to his interpersonal and technical skills, he is highly competent in the overall organization of professional documents. He has flourished in the areas of project administration, capital planning and project management operations.

Mr. Ahmed is a problem-solver with a talent to stream line processes, improve morale, resolve conflict and exceed realistic goals. Most importantly, he always brings personal integrity, honesty and strong work ethics to the project controls profession. His current responsibilities include performing project management and project cost controls services for the Port Authority of NY & NJ. He analyses and coordinates activities with several Program Managers, reviewing project schedules and preparing detailed reports for the Line Department, Project Management Office and the Office of the Chief Operating Officer. With a strong background in IT and knowledge of project management, Mr. Ahmed is value added to projects and project managers from the conception.


 </bio>
 <certificate>
  EIT
  Fundamentals Engineering
  
 </certificate>
 <image>
  Maqsood.jpg
 </image>
 <expertise>
  CPM Scheduling
  Project Management
  Technical Reports
  Capital Planning
  Information Technology
 </expertise>
 <skills>
  Oracle  Primavera P6
  Microsoft Project
  Microsoft Office
  SAP Net Weaver
 </skills>
 <work>
  Project Control Engineer
  The Port Authority of New York & New Jersey
  May
  2014
  Present
  
  Updated schedules in Oracle?s Primavera project scheduling software on a monthly basis or as needed in concert with assigned project managers;
  Reviewed project status with project managers including scope, schedule and costs;
  Creating and maintaining resource loaded project schedules in Oracle?s Primavera project scheduling software;
  Maintained proper project and activity codes in the Primavera system;
  Assisted assigned project managers in preparation of project proposals for projects, including assistance in the preparation of project budgets; updating project forecasts; establishing, maintaining and closing account codes; and preparing monthly and ad-hoc project/program status and performance reports;
  
  Project Control Engineer
  Toll International LLC
  May
  2013
  May
  2014
  Provided scheduling and project control for a variety of new construction and refurbishing projects in the tri-state area. Activities included preparing detailed schedules from drawings, specs and estimates. Prepared expenditure forecasts resource loading progress tracking and claims investigations reports.
  
  Finance Analyst
  Molinaro Koger LLC
  May
  2012
  May
  2013
  Supervised on/off site global support systems and projects for firms?daily forward exchange transactions across the world.
  
  IT Specialist
  Manhattan College
  August
  2010
  May
  2012
  Administered a 60 user Windows Server 2003/SQL Database that collected and stored all college funds and gift transactions.
  Provided Level I/II technical support to department administrators, directors and Vice-President of Finance.
  Executed an effective working relationship with all levels of departmental staff.
  Standardized the process of budgeting and financing by implementing monthly budget sheets of Network and IT accounts for VP and presented VP with cost cutting solutions for Advancement Office. Back up all daily transactions onto an external data source.
  
 </work>
</record>
<record>
 <name>
  Carmine Leone
 </name>
 <position>
  Senior Project Manager
 </position>
 <education>
  The City College of New York
  BS
  Civil Engineering
  
 </education>
 <bio>
  Carmine Leone is an expert Professional Project Manager with over 41 years of experience guiding construction efforts from planning through close-out. He is a licensed professional engineer (Civil) who began his career at the Federal Emergency Management Agency as a General Engineer. He moved to U.S. Army Corps of Engineers to continue serving our country first as a Civil Engineer and subsequently as a Project Manager, Program Manager and Field Coordinator for recovery efforts.

Carmine has also overseen the integration and application of policies, procedures, and regulations for the Division Headquarters staff. As well as being responsible for preparing Program Management Plans and assuring the ANP Program met schedule, cost and scope objectives established through negotiations with the customer and as noted in the Program Management Plan.

As Civil Engineer, Project Manager and Program Manager, Mr. Leone has been responsible for managing hundreds of construction projects totaling billions of dollars in construction. His work has been performed both in the United States as well as overseas. He spent most of his career at the U.S. Army Corps as Program Manager and Civil Engineer assisting with recovery efforts and previously worked for FEMA as a General Engineer.

His communication skills include the preparation of Program Management plans, Report Writing and leading project management teams to complete projects on time and within budget.


 </bio>
 <certificate>
  NY State Board Professional Engineers
  Professional Engineer
  
 </certificate>
 <image>
  Carmine.jpg
 </image>
 <expertise>
  Program Management
  Report Writing
  Cost Controls
  Earned Value Management
  Quantity Surveying
 </expertise>
 <skills>
  Oracle Primavera P6
  Microsoft Project Professional
  Autodesk AutoCAD
 </skills>
 <work>
  Program Manager
  US Army Corps of Engineer
  February
  2013
  Present
  
  Served as the Acting Executive Officer and the Acting Division Deputy Commander for the North Atlantic Division responsible for the day to day operation of the NAD Executive Office.
  Coordinated with NADs 6 Districts to ensure that our military, civil and support for others programs are being executed on time in under budget. Also served as the key civilian member of the Executive Office Team; providing consultation and advice to the Commander on any issues requiring Executive Office attention.
  
  Program Manager
  US Army Corps of Engineer
  November
  2012
  February
  2013
  Performed the duties of the InfrastructureSystems (IS) Recovery Support Function (RSF) Field Coordinator at the New York State Joint Field Office.
  Facilitated the integration of the capabilities of the Federal Government to support local, State and Tribal governments and other infrastructure owners and operators in their efforts to achieve recovery goals relating to the public engineering of the Nation's infrastructure systems.
  
  Program Manager
  US Army Corps of Engineers
  October
  2011
  June
  2012
  Responsible wereexpanded to include integration and reporting TAD-wide PM efforts for the following programs: MILCON; O&M; AIF; CERP and CN programs throughout Afghanistan.
  Developed action plans for resolution of complex issues concerning program execution within the TAD-A AOR.
  Identified developed and maintained relationships with strategic customers. Also led the TAD-A team in development of the "Enhanced Site Assessment for Afghanistan National Security Forces (ANSF).
  
  Program Manager
  US Army Corps of Engineer
  March
  2010
  September
  2010
  Served as the Supervisory Afghan National Police (ANP) Program Manager (PgM) responsible for the integration of all processes and functions for a program of approximately $1B.
  Received, logged, distributed, returned document deliverables to and from all contractors (engineering and construction) as per processes in place.
  Responsible for assuring the ANP Program met schedule, cost and scope objectives established through negotiations with the customer and as noted in the Program Management Plan.
  
 </work>
</record>
<record>
 <name>
  Arnold Katz
 </name>
 <position>
  Senior Project Manager
 </position>
 <education>
  New Jersey Institute of Technology
  BS
  Civil Engineering
  
 </education>
 <bio>
  Arnold Katz is Vice-President and co-owner of Toll International PC, a Toll International LLC affiliated company. Arnold has held a Bachelor's degree in Engineering Technology, Civil Engineering and Construction Management from the Newark College of Engineering, New Jersey Institute of Technology since 1980 and possesses over 45 years of high-level experiences as a Project Executive and is an industry leader with respect to the Management of construction projects in the power and utilities sector. He is also actively engaged in other capital intensive projects in the public as well as private sectors both in the United States and in International markets.

Arnold's experience encompasses practice of civil engineering and construction management in the Environmental discipline on a number of projects in the power, energy and utilities sector. Arnold is no stranger to the regulatory compliance necessary for public sector agencies and has had plenty of experience in working alongside notable public agencies such as the Department of Environmental Protection in the State of New York.

Arnold is at ease in terms of building strong and effective project teams targeted to clients' specific goals for their capital construction projects. Arnold's long career has proven his exceptional ability to execute large and complex projects and brings particular expertise in Solicitation, Negotiation, and Administration of Contracts.


 </bio>
 <certificate>
  New York State & New Jersey
  Professional Engineer
  
  Constr. Management Asso. of America
  Certified Construction Manager
  
 </certificate>
 <image>
  Arnold.jpg
 </image>
 <expertise>
  Project Planning
  Bidding & Contracting
  Critical Path Method Scheduling
  Value Engineering
  Contract Management
 </expertise>
 <skills>
  Oracle Primavera P6, CM
  Microsoft Project Professional
  Microsoft Office
  Sage Estimating (Timberline)
 </skills>
 <work>
  Director, Project Management
  Toll International LLC
  April
  2012
  Present
  
  Directs Strategies & Teams for managing projects in the power, industrial, energy, pharmaceutical, and public works sectors with proven project management practices and with unique project controls techniques wherever applicable.
  
  Construction Manager
  Shaw Environmental & Infrastructure
  July
  2011
  February
  2012
  Established the execution stratedgy & construction plan for the restoration of a large sewage treatment plant in NYC after a major fire incident
  Managed field staff and in coordination with other consultants, stabilized the damaged plant and worked with the engineering firm to develop the scope of restoration work
  
  Senior Construction Manager
  Shaw Environmental & Infrastructure
  April
  2010
  February
  2012
  Senior Construction Executive accountable for the completion of the upgrade of the Newtown Creek Water Treatment Plant in Brooklyn, NY.
  Managed a staff of 65 professionals to administer and coordinate the project being executed for the NYC DEP under 12 contracts worth $1.2 Billion combined
  Activities under direct control include inspection and acceptance of work, coordination with designers and the NYDEP
  
  Senior Vice President
  Haugland Infrastructure Group
  January
  2009
  October
  2009
  Responsible for the development of the execution strategies and the Management of construction projects in the electric power and associated industries in the US.
  Responsible for the development of the scope of work, identification of appropriate tem members, subcontractors, & partners for all aspects of the project
  
  Business Partner
  The Hammerhead Group
  January
  2006
  September
  2006
  Responsible for the development of the Hammerhead Group as a Construction Management & Construction Claims consulting company
  
 </work>
</record>
<record>
 <name>
  Kambiz Nassiri
 </name>
 <position>
  Senior Project Manager
 </position>
 <education>
  NY Institute of Technology
  MS
  Energy Management
  
  City University of New York
  BE
  Mechanical Engineering
  
 </education>
 <bio>
  Kambiz Nassiri is a licensed professional project manager with Port Authority experience and a successful track record of over 25 years managing large scale complex projects. He has Bachelor’s degree in Mechanical Engineering from CUNY City College and a Master of Science in Energy Management from NYIT. Mr. Kambiz is a licensed Professional Engineer and has achieved Project Management Professional (PMP) and LEED AP BC+C industry certifications.

He has extensive experience related to leadership, program management, project management, planning, engineering, energy conservation, sustainable LEED design, and construction of complex multidisciplinary projects involving major structures.

His engineering and managerial responsibilities have extended over a large range of projects, including commercial, high rise structures, transportation facilities, educational buildings, historic landmarks, and industrial buildings.


 </bio>
 <certificate>
  NY State Board Professional Engineers
  Professional Engineer
  
  Project Management Institute
  Project Management Professional
  
 </certificate>
 <image>
  Kambiz.jpg
 </image>
 <expertise>
  Contract Negotiations
  Regulatory Compliance
  Project Management
  Cost Control
  Due Diligence Reports
 </expertise>
 <skills>
  Oracle Primavera P6, CM
  Microsoft Office
  Autodesk AutoCAD
 </skills>
 <work>
  Toll International LLC
  Senior Project Manager
  June
  2013
  Present
  
  Hold P&L responsibility for engineering of complex and visible projects, managing large design teams, and overseeing design work.
  Prepare, implement, and monitor best engineering practices including design integrations and unique solutions
  Royal Atlantis Resort & Residences, Dubai: 3.5 M square feet, $4B Construction of Two, 47 Story luxury Hotel and Residential Towers over a 3 story common Podium building.
  Bronx Criminal Court, Bronx, New York: 1.1 M square feet, multi-MEP bid packages.
  99 Hudson Street, Jersey City, NJ- 80 Story (tallest in NJ), 1.3M square feet multi- family residential with luxury amenity floors.
  
  Project Manager
  Thornton Tomasetti Associates
  January
  2013
  June
  2013
  Task Leader at Loss Prevention Group
  Assisted insurance companies to analyze pre and post loss risks
  Prepared damage and property claims arising from natural and man-made perils.
  Drawing on vast MEP expertise, offered solutions to complex issues through investigation of damage
  Performed cause and origin analyses, and Engineering assessments for reinstatement of damaged buildings, building code upgrade analyses and for responding to emerging specialized claims such as those for more modern, LEED-certified structures.
  
  Program Manager
  Cosentini Associates
  June
  2007
  December
  2012
  Served as Program Manager for direction of all aspects of MEP engineering projects, supervision of large teams, reporting directly to company President and Exec. VP
  Oversaw all activities, and contributed to peak annual revenue.
  
  Senior Program Director
  Earth Tech
  January
  2005
  June
  2007
  Managed technical teams on multiple projects and handled client-side issues
  
  Program Manager
  Mott MacDonald Group
  January
  2001
  January
  2005
  Served as Project Manager on a major rehabilitation of a ventilating system.
  
 </work>
</record>
<record>
 <name>
  Raif Ahmad
 </name>
 <position>
  Senior Project Manager
 </position>
 <education>
  New Jersey Institute of Technology
  MS
  Construction Management
  
  Minya University
  BS
  Civil & Structural Engineering
  
 </education>
 <bio>
  Raif Ahmad is hereby proposed to be Toll International's Lead Scheduler for this contract opportunity. Raif Ahmad possesses more than 20 years of experiences in the construction industry played more specific roles in the capacity of Scheduling, Project Control, Contract Management and Estimating. Raif's background as an academic has netted him an impressive Double-Masters' diplomas in Construction Management, Water Resources, in addition to his qualification as a Civil Engineer. Raif is also certified by the Project Management Institute as a Project Scheduling Professional (PSP) as well as a (PMP) Project Management Professional, in addition.

Raif Ahmad's career has placed him into impactful positions on projects in the vertical construction market in the Middle-East. He is no stranger to big-budget projects and their implementation in extreme environments with resource intense and cost-loaded schedules. His experiences include work accomplished on Residential and Commercial vertical construction, Aviation Projects, Highways, Railways and other major infrastructure assignments.

To further highlight his experienced ability, Raif Ahmad brings specialty expertise in Critical Path Method (CPM) based Scheduling as well as in the Program Evaluation & Review Technique (PERT) from his prior body of work. Raif Ahmad's oversight on this program would assure the application of state-of-the-art methods, techniques and procedures to ensure the overall quality assurance for the Port Authority's projects.


 </bio>
 <certificate>
  Project Management Institute
  Planning Scheduling Professional
  
  Project Management Institute
  Project Management Professional
  
 </certificate>
 <image>
  Raif.jpg
 </image>
 <expertise>
  Project Planning
  Control Resource Management
  Critical Path Method Scheduling
  Program Evaluation
  Review Technique
 </expertise>
 <skills>
  Oracle Primavera P6, CM
  Microsoft Project Professional
  Microsoft Office
  Sage Estimating (Timberline)
 </skills>
 <work>
  Senior Scheduler
  Toll International LLC
  March
  2013
  Present
  
  Develops and provides construction schedules for New Jersey Transit's Sandy-Recovery Program
  
  Construction Manager
  Qatari Diar
  March
  2015
  Present
  
  Client's representative for their projects in Doha, Qatar
  Assisted Project Manager & Engineer
  Generated cash flow reports and resource allocation via Primvera
  Ensured under-budget and on-schedule delivery of the projects
  
  Scheduling Engineer
  JCMS Incorporated
  June
  2008
  Present
  
  Client's representative for their projects in Doha, Qatar
  Assisted Project Manager & Engineer
  Generated cash flow reports and resource allocation via Primvera
  Ensured under-budget and on-schedule delivery of the projects
  
  Project Officer
  New York School Construction Authority
  June
  2008
  Present
  
  Reviewed contractors' baseline schedules, impacted schedules, and recovery schedules
  Performed Time Impact Analysis
  Contract management
  Cost Estimating and Risk Analysis using PERTMaster
  
  Scheduler; Estimator
  PBS&J
  September
  2006
  June
  2008
  Reviewed and analysed capital project baseline schedules and schedule updates for school projects
  Monitored project progress by way of direct observation and documentation
  
  Project Manager
  Qatar Building Engineering Company
  February
  1999
  April
  2006
  Construction of 20 Bachelor and 14 married Senior Staff Bunga
  lows with their services and Infrastructure, Site
  Management, Shop Drawing Preparing.
  Project scheduling using MS Project2000
  
 </work>
</record>
<record>
 <name>
  Pedro Contreras
 </name>
 <position>
  Senior Project Manager
 </position>
 <education>
  Universidad Catolica Andres Bello
  BS
  Civil Engineering
  
 </education>
 <bio>
  A Project Manager and Project Controls/Cost Control Specialist with over twenty-five years of diverse experience in managing and establishing Project Controls/ Cost Controls Systems for projects, portfolio of projects and programs in the Oil & Gas, for Owners and Engineering, Procurement and Construction Companies.

Strong project management knowledge and best practices foundation: Bachelor degree in Civil engineering (P.Eng), Project Management Professional (PMP) and Certified Cost Professional (CCP). Strong change knowledge and change management foundation: Change Management Registered Practitioner and Master Certificate in Systems Design and Project Leadership (Cornell)

20+ years of experience in project cost controls functions supporting the delivery of medium to large-scale projects and portfolio of projects and programs.

Large, diverse and complex experience in project and portfolio controls functions and processes which include Cost Estimating, Cost Monitoring, Cost Forecasting (cash flow), Management of Change, Planning, Scheduling, Budgeting, , Risk Management, Project Administration, earned value management, reporting and overall cost control and control services.

Led and supervised teams of up to 25 resources including career growth, coaching and ensured compliance of all project controls team members regarding company QA and HSE policies.

Represented departments as a key contact interacting with stakeholders on significant and complex project governance and controls matters. Ability and experience to drive organizations towards high levels of excellence in Project Controls and Management.


 </bio>
 <certificate>
  NY State Board Professional Engineers
  Professional Engineer
  
 </certificate>
 <image>
  Pedro.jpg
 </image>
 <expertise>
  Cost Estimating
  Cost Monitoring
  Planning
  Scheduling
 </expertise>
 <skills>
  Microsoft Project
  SAP
  Oracle Primavera
  Enterprise Resource Management Systems (ERP)
 </skills>
 <work>
  Director
  PC&M
  January
  2017
  Present
  
  Consultant and hands on services in project controls, and application of knowledge in project management best practices (PMBOK/PMI and Total Cost Management TCM/AACEi ), Change Management and Business Analysis and Improvement.
  Seeking opportunities to make a difference by the means of extensive expertise in project controls combined with project management best practices, change management and business analysis and improvement skills and knowledge.
  Services are aligned with globally accepted standards organizations such as PMI, AACEi and Change Management Institute (CMI);
  
  Senior Manager
  Emerson Process Management
  January
  2013
  September
  2016
  Reporting directly to the Engineering Center (CEC) Director.
  Consolidated a solid Project Controls culture to support gross profit target achievement in 2014 and 2015 with an outstanding level of Operational effectiveness achieved (+95%).
  Led and Implemented Canada Engineering Center Project Controls System, including governance, processes definition, procedures completion, optimization of processes and development of tools.
  
  Cost Lead
  Devon Energy Canada
  October
  2010
  January
  2013
  Developed project controls, policies and processes to ensure full customer satisfaction.
  Managed resources and Subject Matter Expert for budgeting and cost control of major programs. Trusted advisor on key initiatives that enabled the organization to implement high-impact business processes focused on improving budget, cost control and cost forecasting processes.
  New cost department organized and improved to provide quality and timely program/project cost controls and reporting services for four different major programs and portfolio of projects (yearly budget: above 800 MM$, overall budget: above 8,000 MM$). Group of Senior and Junior project controls specialists coached and trained to accomplish this goal.
  
  Project Controls Specialist
  acobs Engineering Inc.
  June
  2007
  September
  2010
  Established and updated project controls systems for budgeting, budget allocation, commitment control, management of change, incurred cost and cost forecast of the project total installed cost (TIC), including preparation of cash flow and commitment profiles for the total installed cost of the project.
  Prepared and updated the project cash flow including deviation analysis and an accurate expenditure forecast with variations under 5%.
  Coordinated Jacobs Administration Control and Reporting System (progress, cost and compliance) with optimization of gross margin for Jacobs’s services (GP and Margin Analysis reporting).
  
 </work>
</record>
<record>
 <name>
  Bryan Tyska
 </name>
 <position>
  Project Manager
 </position>
 <education>
  New Jersey Institute of Technology
  MBA
  Finance
  
  New Jersey Institute of Technology
  BS
  Civil Engineering
  
 </education>
 <bio>
  Bryan has over 15 years of experience as an engineer and 5 years in project management. He has had the opportunity to work on several projects such as Spuyten-Duybil Mechanical and Electrical rehab, East River Tunnels rehab, Penn Access, and the NYSDOT bridge rehab project. He has a BSCE in Civil Engineering from NJIT with a minor in Business Management. He has passed both the FE and PE exams and thus he is a PE in the state of NJ. Bryan has also obtained an MBA with a concentration in Finance from NJIT. Bryan along with having a PE has also been rewarded a PMP certification. Bryan has a work history of 8 years with Armtrak and recently has joined the Toll team to be one of the key members that have made Toll thrive.

Bryan's expertise lies in structural engineering, contract management, and Transportation. He has developed these list of skills through his experience on multiple projects such as the Penn Station Enhancement Program and working along the NEC.


 </bio>
 <certificate>
  Project Management Institute
  Project Management Professional
  
  NY State Board Professional Engineers
  Professional Engineer
  
 </certificate>
 <image>
  Bryan.jpg
 </image>
 <expertise>
  Structural Engineering
  Contract Management
  Transportation
  Structural Analysis
 </expertise>
 <skills>
  Autodesk AutoCAD
  Microsoft Office
  Railroad Design
 </skills>
 <work>
  Construction Manager
  Amtrak
  October
  2017
  Present
  
  Management of several large capital construction projects: Spuyten-Duyvil Mechanical,Electrical rehab, East River Tunnels rehab, Penn Access
  DEveloped planning and management required for NYSDOT bridge rehab.
  
  Senior Engineer
  Amtrak
  February
  2015
  September
  2017
  Responsible for the maintenance and upgrades of Penn Station New York.
  Includes, but is not limited to: HVAC, structural, mechanical, electrical, and plumbing concerns.
  
  Senior Engineer of Fire and Life Safety
  Amtrak
  November
  2013
  February
  2015
  Responsible for maintaining and replacing all fire and life safety equipment in and around Penn Station New York, North River Tunnels, and East River tunnels. This includes, but is not limited to pumps, fire standpipe, and fans. Other support systems include sprinkler systems, SCADA, lighting, electrical distribution, electrical back-up systems, and tunnel structural elements.
  Important subset of my duties is SANDY related replacements of integral equipment that was severely damaged by the event.
  
  Engineer
  Amtrak
  June
  2009
  November
  2013
  Manage operations and structures along the North East Corridor (NEC) for Amtrak.
  Includes but is not limited to steel repair, bridge deck replacements, entire bridge replacements, bridge rehab (anything from bearing clean-up to abutment repair), bridge inspections, culvert rehab, maintenance on movable bridges, general building repair, ballast mitigation, railroad tie replacement, and retaining wall installation.
  Consistently manage between 20 and 70 employees.
  Worked all along the NEC which includes Boston to Washington DC and two smaller branches from New York City to Albany and New Haven, CT to Springfield, MA.
  
  Intern
  Tilcon New York Inc.
  June
  2006
  May
  2009
  Various field work and administrative duties.
  Accounting work which included time sheets, invoicing the Port Authority for reimbursable work, and record keeping of projects.
  Take-offs, surveying field work.
  
 </work>
</record>
<record>
 <name>
  Rick Marden
 </name>
 <position>
  Technology Implementation Specialist
 </position>
 <education>
  St. Joseph's College
  BA
  Mathematics & Computer Systems
  
 </education>
 <bio>
  Rick Marden possesses over 20 years of professional experiences in Business Intelligence, Data Analytics, Software Programming, Customization, Support, and training for Project/Contract Management Software solutions as a premier  IT Consultant. Rick Marden is a true academic, having majored in Mathematics and Computer Systems at St. Josephs College. Rick's clear standout attribute for the serious consideration of his candidacy from this proposal was earned immediately following his education, when in 1995 he joined Primavera Systems Inc. as  a Technical Consultant and Support specialist. He was part of their organization for over 6 years through two different positions before moving on to other private sector opportunities as well as public-sector work.

Rick Marden's specialties lie in report development, business intelligence, data integration, and advanced SQL database programming. The ability to communicate to those with all levels of technical background is a unique quality found in the industry which, along with my strong analytical approach to problems, has attributed to Rick's success in the industry as a leading provider of software solutions. He has obtained most of the technical skills needed in the field of technology consulting. These skills include managing databases through SQL on servers such as Microsoft Access as well as transferring data to Primavera P6 for public organizations such as the New York School Construction Authority. Having the ability to manipulate databases and other Primavera software has also made the services provided by Marden an incredible asset to the flow of management for any construction project. 

With his familiarity with the technology and the knowledge of specific needs required to be successful in the public-sector, Rick Marden can deliver more than adequately to the demands of the New York Power Authority.


 </bio>
 <certificate>
  Oracle
  Primaver Implementation Specialist
  
 </certificate>
 <image>
  Rick.jpg
 </image>
 <expertise>
  Program Planning
  Software Implementation
  Systems Analysis
  Software Testing
  Earned Value Management
 </expertise>
 <skills>
  Oracle Primavera P6, CM
  Microsoft Project Professional
  Microsoft SQL Server
 </skills>
 <work>
  Business Analyst / Consultant
  Toll International LLC
  January
  2013
  Present
  
  Developed a custom integration for a regional airport authority that inserts and updates activities and resource assignments to Oracle Primavera P6 from documents in Oracle Primavera Contract Management (OPCM).
  Includes a two-way integration with the airport’s financial system, Microsoft Dynamics Navision.
  Created all functional and technical requirements documents, and developed the integration using SQL stored procedures.
  
  Technology Analyst
  NYC School Construction Authority
  February
  2009
  March
  2012
  Planning / development / testing / support related to upgrading 2,000+ plus projects from Expedition v8.59 to Contract Manager v13
  SQL programming for enhancing the use of the application by customizing to SCA standards
  Ongoing report development and conversion of many custom reports to ensure they continue to run as expected after the upgrade
  Advanced technical support for escalated issues in both v8.59 and v13
  
  Business Analyst / Consultant
  InsideOut Project Solutions
  March
  2012
  March
  2013
  Developed advanced cost reports using Oracle Business Intelligence (BI) Publisher
  Analyst / Consultant / Programmer / Report Developer (Various Projects)
  Converted custom reports to OPCM Business Intelligence Edition (v14) from InfoMaker report format for a private construction company
  Converted the OPCM system from v10 to 12.1 to 13 for a large public transportation agency - Tasks included testing, training, custom report conversion, transition to HTTPS SSL secure server technology, and database migration from Sybase SQL Anywhere to MS SQL Server
  Developed a data migration for a state power authority using Primavera API from an in-house Access based system to Primavera P6 and OPCM v11
  Custom report development / support for many clients using BI Publisher, InfoMaker, and other report writing / query tools
  
 </work>
</record>
<record>
 <name>
  Syed Rahman
 </name>
 <position>
  IT Management Specialist
 </position>
 <education>
  New York University
  MS
  Business Project Management
  
  Dhaka University
  BA
  English
  
 </education>
 <bio>
  Syed Rahman is a professional project manager with over 23 years of experience managing information technology projects. He is able to lead teams and collaborate with department’s heads to optimize the operations and achieve the targeted result. In addition to his extensive experience in Project/program Management, He is adept at developing Information Technology Project Business Requirements and is skilled with strategic planning and portfolio management. Syed has a successful track record of team building, process re-engineering, development, creating/implementing the corporate governance and policy, and post-merger integration.

Syed has the Operational Leadership strategic direction to IT and Business team. Direct responsibility to monitor progress and maturity level of the organization to meet targets. Establish new liaisons with various other departments and units to secure long-term performance improvement. He can also Lead high-level negotiations with stakeholders to deliver complex assignments and handle issues they become problems. His experience allows him to make deals with vendors concerning commercial terms and contracts and with lawyers concerning disputes and problems. Syed is an expert in developing strategic partnerships. Highly skilled at follow through on objectives and able to explain and justify expenditures and Return on Investment (ROI) to achieve goals.


 </bio>
 <certificate>
  AAPM
  Certified International Project Manager
  
  AAPM
  Master Project Manager
  
 </certificate>
 <image>
  Syed.jpg
 </image>
 <expertise>
  Database Management
  Project Management
  Data Migration
 </expertise>
 <skills>
  Microsoft Project
  Microsoft Office
  HTML
  Java
  Primavera Oracle P6
 </skills>
 <work>
  Director of IT Management
  Toll International LLC
  February
  2015
  Present
  
  Working closely with the CIO and Senior Leadership team to continue the development and execution of significant growth and expansion plans inclusive of the new business development and upcoming Project throughout the hospital in day to day operation.
  Enforces the highest standard of quality control conducting regular site surveys/inspections with members of the business development team. Additionally, follows up to resolve problem situations that arise in this process. Implements quality assurance methods and procedures, actively oversees and assesses quality levels achieved at each project/business process.
  
  Senior IT Program Manager
  L'Oreal
  April
  2014
  January
  2015
  Provided the strategic business guidance and support to all the Global Projects/Program, according to their size and nature of the business and develop and maintain the Requirement Tractability Matrixes Document (RTMD) along with Business Design Documentation (BDD) based on the business requirements to justify the business continuity process.
  Built Omni channel initiatives and infrastructure bridging the gap between online and in store retail with technology including BOPUS (Buy Online Pick Up in Store), SDD (Same Day Delivery) and Order Management Systems (OMS).
  
  Senior IT Program Manager
  J.P. Morgan Chase
  October
  2013
  April
  2014
  Utilize negotiation skills to drive project team and make decisions in a timely manner to deliver project as to agreed scope, schedule and budget.
  Partner with corporate planning to track project/program budgets at a detailed level. Lead and drive issue resolution, risk identification and mitigation, change and dependency management.
  Encourage the active use of a strong risk management framework with the project teams and stakeholders. Create the Project Charter (to include clear project objectives, goals and deliverables), Project Scope Plan, Project Schedule Plan, Project communication plan, Project Quality Management Plan and Project Risk Management Plan to run the project according to proper business standard and maintain the right direction of Project Life Cycle (PLC) to complete the work on time and under budget.
  
  Program Manager
  Ultra Mobile
  May
  2013
  September
  2013
  Work closely with the vendor/contractor to ensure the right quality product delivery according to business requirements, monitor the project progress, control and monitor the quality of the product and other related subjects.
  Create the proper documentation and get the sign of from the IT/Development Group, Quality Assurance (QA) and Business and Production team to release the software/application according to the business/client’s requirements.
  Manage client projects towards ambitious goals, develop and manage high level client relationships
  
 </work>
</record>
<record>
 <name>
  Abdul H. Memon
 </name>
 <position>
  Risk Evaluation Specialist
 </position>
 <education>
  University of Alberta
  ME
  Construction Engg. & Management
  
  Mehran University of Engineering
  BE
  Civil Engineering
  
 </education>
 <bio>
  Abdul has about 20 years of professional experience in Planning/ Scheduling and Coordination, Resource allocation and Budgeting, Cost Analysis and Risk Analysis, Monitoring and Tracking of Buildings Projects including High Rise Buildings (20+ Floors) and Five Star Hotel (20+ Floors) and associated Infrastructure work, Water, Sewerage Lines and Roads Projects, Overhead and Underground Power Transmission and Distribution Lines and Substations Projects, Pump Stations, Water and Sewerage Treatment Plants, Pre-cast Concrete, Modular Work Packages and Structural Steel Projects, Oil and Gas New Facilities Development Projects. He has a Bachelor of Science in Civil Engineering, Master of Engineering (MEng.) (Specialization in Construction Engineering & Management), and a Master of Business Administration (MBA). He certifications include Professional (PSP), Cost Professional (CCP) and Earned Value Professional (EVP). He has worked in the construction as well as EPC environment. Abdul is also familiar with Lump Sum/ Fixed Price, Time & Material and Cost Reimbursable Contracts and has worked in Design-Bid-Build as well as Design-Build project delivery systems. He is involved in Material Bills Rate Analysis and Cost Estimates. Abdul is well acquainted with Project Management techniques and tools. He has also worked on Risk Analysis Software Primavera Risk Management (Pert Master), Linear Planning and Scheduling software TILOS.


 </bio>
 <certificate>
  Project Management Institute
  Risk Management Professional
  
  AACE
  Planning Scheduling Professional
  
 </certificate>
 <image>
  Abdul.jpg
 </image>
 <expertise>
  Risk Analysis
  Project Management
  Scheduling
  Construction Engineering
 </expertise>
 <skills>
  Primavera Project Planner P3
  MS Project
  TILOS
  Eco Sys
  Micrsoft Office
 </skills>
 <work>
  Senior Planner Scheduler
  K&L Engineering Consulting
  July
  2017
  April
  2018
  Work on New York Power Authority Smart Generations and Transmission (SG&T) Projects.
  Prepare, maintain and monitor resource loaded Level 4 EPC schedules.
  
  Senior Planner Scheduler
  Gemini Coportation
  February
  2017
  April
  2017
  Developed, maintained and monitored resource loaded turnaround schedule in Primavera P6 Version 8.
  Monitored planned, earned and actual/incurred man-hours and cost.
  Developed and monitored three-part curves (Planned, Earned, Incurred and Forecast Curves).
  
  Senior Planner Scheduler
  Edmonton
  March
  2013
  December
  2016
  Coordinated with engineering firms in developing the work breakdown structure for construction work packages.
  Ensured tasks are coded by the project work breakdown structure and code of accounts for cost and schedule integration and analysis.
  Prepared, maintained and monitored complex engineering, procurement and construction project schedules.
  Worked on Primavera P6 version 7 and Version 8.3 for planning and scheduling EPC schedules.
  Identified activities, evaluated and established logical sequencing between the activities
  Defined and developed critical paths, conducted total float analysis and reported project management status of critical activities, variance analysis and schedule risks.
  Conducted Risk Analysis, “what-if” scenarios, recovery plans, contingency planning and schedule compression techniques.
  Provided recommendations for corrective action due to delays in certain aspects of the project.
  Prepared and maintained resource loaded Baseline Master Schedule based on control man-hours and control budget.
  
  Project Controls Lead
  IMV Projects
  September
  2011
  March
  2013
  Analyzed and generated cost reports in in-house project controls software.
  Created, maintained and updated resource loaded EPC schedules highlighting the sequence of all tasks to be performed.
  Loaded Resources and Cost data into schedules and prepared S- Curve based on Man-hours and Cost.
  Prepared and monitored incurred cost in in-house project controls software against planned and earned value and developed forecasts of the Projects.
  Employed Earned Value Management Techniques in analyzing and forecasting the cost of the Project.
  
 </work>
</record>
<record>
 <name>
  Samir Rafla
 </name>
 <position>
  Claims Management Specialist
 </position>
 <education>
  Minya University
  BS
  Civil Engineering
  
 </education>
 <bio>
  Samir Rafla has held 16 years of continuous professional experience in the construction industry, implementing the most current Project Scheduling and Project Controls techniques for projects in a number of business sectors. With his scheduling skills and planning acumen, Samir has often been a part of high-performance teams striving to achieve excellence in the optimal balance between efficiency and quality of accomplished work. Through his years of work experiences and the soundness of his ability, Samir brings an appreciable repertoire of both technical as well as soft-skills and communicating ability to this proposal.

Samir Rafla has developed a deep understanding of project performance indicators, as well as strong analytical and problem-solving skills, which have allowed him to consistently achieve a proven track record in the field of Project Scheduling and Planning. During the course of his notable experiences, Samir has also had the particular experience of using forensic techniques for claims analysis.

The most noteworthy of Samir's experiences include his scheduling-associated work contributions on an aviation project for an International Airport in Africa. He was also involved in a similar capacity for work on the flagship Grand Museum in Egypt. He currently serves the MTA's NYCT, on their Brooklyn Expressway PS-281 project on his current assignment with Toll International LLC.

Samir's particular specialties include Oracle Primavera P6 Contract Management, Risk Analysis, Project Controls Techniques, Project Resource Management, Budgeting, Financial Control, Forensic Claims Analyses, Feasibility Studies, Bidding, Evidence Law, Sources / Regimes of Obligation as well as Delay related claims & disputes in the construction industry.


 </bio>
 <certificate>
  Project Management Institute
  Planning Scheduling Professional
  
  Project Management Institute
  Project Management Professional
  
 </certificate>
 <image>
  Samir.jpg
 </image>
 <expertise>
  Project Planning & Control
  Resource Management
  FDIC Contracting
  Feasibility Studies
  Forensic Claims Analysis
  Systems Design & Architecture
 </expertise>
 <skills>
  Oracle Primavera P6
  Microsoft Project Professional
  Microsoft Office
  Sage Estimating(Sage 100 & 300)
 </skills>
 <work>
  Senior Scheduler
  Toll Internationall LLC
  January
  2019
  Present
  
  Develops construction schedules for MTA-NYCT Design/Build projects
  Assists PM towards achieving control over the project aspects of time, cost, and earned value
  Provides forensic claims analysis
  Provides Schedule updates with the associated narrative
  Manages planning issues with the project team and other stakeholders.
  Provides substantiation and particulars to the Contractors planning submissions.
  Establishes monthly reporting procedures and updates to client and senior management
  Prepares weekly and monthly reports for team and senior management
  
  Planning & Forensic Claims Manager
  BAM InternationalBAM International
  March
  2015
  January
  2019
  Provided management assistance to the PM with respect to PMI standards
  Generated Master Schedule and provided periodic revisions
  Led planning team for the delivery of the key and other required tasks
  Provided schedule progress, KPI's and earned value updates
  Performed Risk analyses using Monte Carlo Simulations
  Managed issues with subcontractors
  Developed forensic planning and claims analyses
  
  Deputy Planning Manager
  Besix - Orascom
  March
  2012
  March
  2015
  Generated Master Schedule and provided periodic revisions
  Managed schedule timeline and resolved all planning related issues
  Developed linear scheduling for resource utilization
  Generated Forensic Planning and Claims Analyses for the project
  Established key deliverable milestones in coordination with upper management
  Provided forecasting (personnel, material, funds) for the project lifetime
  Provided forensic planning related assistance to DAB Members
  
  Senior Planning Engineer
  Orascom - Hassan Allam
  November
  2017
  February
  2012
  Assisted with preparation, management, and overview of strategic planning
  Assisted with design, procurement, and construction schedules for the project
  Reviewed scheduling trends to identify potential problems & corrective action
  
  Planning Engineer
  Orascom Construction Industries
  May
  2004
  Construction
  2006
  Prepared construction schedules and provided periodic progress updates
  Reviewed invoices and prepared comparison sheets for final review
  Calculated productivity rates
  
 </work>
</record>
<record>
 <name>
  Sandro Correia
 </name>
 <position>
  Document Control Specialist
 </position>
 <education>
  Federal University of Rio de Janeiro
  BA
  Business Administration
  
 </education>
 <bio>
  Sandro Correia currently serves as Document Control Program Manager with Toll International. With Toll, he has worked on the South East Queens Stormwater Project and was a consultant to the Department of Design and Construction. As a consultant he developed a document management plan, documentation standards, procedures and working instructions for the program including file structure, document layout, storage location, naming conventions, and developing workflows.  With Toll, he has also trained DDC high manager level staff (“training the trainers”) on how to use the SEQ DDC SharePoint site. With over 15 years of experience in document and project controls, Sandro has worked with a range of companies in the public-sector allowing him to be aware of the specific demands of federal projects.

Sandro Correia is more than proficient with AutoCad, photoshop, SharePoint, and other documentation software. Being able to speak 5 languages (Japanese, Spanish, English, French, and Portuguese) contributes to Sandro's ability to effectively handle any cultural, political and economic difference,  allowing him to successfully work with any kind of community.

His prior experience in producing oil and gas project's data-books permits for the ability to embrace new technologies, meet emerging market demands, respond effectively to changing conditions, apply continuous improvement techniques and create new business opportunities. Also, his extensive experience in engineering documents (drawings, specifications, etc.) focused on fields of Energy, Oil, and Gas (including Oilsands projects) make Sandro an excellent Toll International Document and Project Controls employee.


 </bio>
 <certificate>
  Project Management Institute
  Project Management Professional
  
 </certificate>
 <image>
  Sandro.jpg
 </image>
 <expertise>
  Oil and Gas documentation
  Engineering documents
  Project Management
  Oil & Gas project books
 </expertise>
 <skills>
  Oracle Primavera P6, CM
  Bentley Microstation
  Autodesk AutoCAD
  Documentum
  EIM-Directa
 </skills>
 <work>
  Document Control Coordinator
  Toll International LLC
  June
  2018
  Present
  
  Developing of document management plan, documentation standards, procedures and work instructions for the program including file structure, document layout, storage location and naming conventions, developing work flows.
  Maintaining standard document revisions.Training DDC high manager level staff (“training the trainers”) on how to use the SEQ DDC SharePoint site.
  Designing and creation of the SEQ DDC SharePoint hosted site.
  Assisting the Program Controls Manager producing the Monthly Progress Report.
  
  Document Control Coordinator
  Thomas Group Inc
  June
  2017
  February
  2018
  Preparation and control of construction Field Installation Work Packages (FIWP), preparation and updating of progress tracker.
  Receiving, monitoring and completing all drawings and documentation for the construction.
  Setting up document control project files.
  Assisting in preparation of project estimating Take-off as well as Turnover documentation
  
  Document Control Manager
  Girassol Apoio Maritimo Ltda
  August
  2015
  August
  2017
  Developed and implemented the Document Management Plan, involved in writing and maintaining document control procedures, standards and work processes/flows. Also involved in the creation, implementation, use and compliant state of the Electronic Document Management System (SharePoint), including senior management training and production of a SharePoint User Guide.
  Assisted the project team in monitoring submittals on the project, creating and maintaining submittal logs and control paper and digital distribution to project.
  
  Senior Document Controller
  Imperial Oil
  July
  2013
  July
  2015
  Provided document control support to all Site Stakeholders including Operations and Construction Contractors in accordance with business processes. Point of contact for all Site external and internal requests for documentation, providing document control support to Operations and Construction Contractors.
  Received, logged, distributed, returned document deliverables to and from all contractors (engineering and construction) as per processes in place.
  
 </work>
</record>
<record>
 <name>
  Jeff Cook
 </name>
 <position>
  Technology Implementation Specialist
 </position>
 <education>
  State University of New York
  BS
  Physical Education
  
 </education>
 <bio>
  Mr. Jeff Cook leverages a background working in Information Technology where he developed expert-level skills managing and administering computer systems and databases, using analytical skills to solve complex problems, along with custom software development and user experience design. Around ten years ago, he transitioned to business consulting where he has established himself as a skilled systems architect with experience designing, configuring, and deploying project controls systems, information portals, and various database driven applications. He has served as technical lead on multiple projects, managing requirements and bridging the gap between client stakeholders and technical resources. Mr. Cook facilitates client meetings and coordinates project team members with a servant-leader style based on agile framework principles. His expertise around PMWeb and other PMIS systems,such as E-Builder and Unifier, have been utilized in configuration and deployment projects, data migration efforts, and software assessments. He understands the technical side of configuration and development including the Software Development Life Cycle (SLDC) but also has a wealth of knowledge regarding the business aspects of managing large capital construction programs and projects as well as techniques for achieving business process optimization. Additionally, he  leverages  expert  knowledge  of  software  for  management  of  team  collaboration,  user  acceptance  testing,  software documentation, and cost & schedule management to see projects through from initial planning to final production deployment.


 </bio>
 <certificate>
  Scrum.org
  Professional Scrum Master
  
 </certificate>
 <image>
  Jeff.jpg
 </image>
 <expertise>
  IT Project Management
  Database Design
  Data Integration
  Data Migration
 </expertise>
 <skills>
  PMWeb
  Oracle Primavera P6, CM 13
  Unifier
  E-Builder
  Microsoft Office
 </skills>
 <work>
  Project Manager
  Northwell Health
  November
  2018
  June
  2019
  Managed Oracle Primavera system including Unifier, P6, Analytics, BI Publisher.
  Provided system expertise for system upgrades, configuration changes, data integration updates.
  Managed the upgrade from version 17 to 18. Helped re-design Budget approval process and provided oversight to internal Unifier /P6 team as well as consultants.
  Lead data migration efforts to modernize existing projects. Setup Unifier project and portfolio level cash flow using P6 data integration.
  
  Consultant
  PM Solutions
  February
  2017
  Present
  
  Served on several PMIS implementations for several software solutions including PMWeb, Oracle Primavera Unifier and e- builder. for several years.
  Working on a Unifier implementation for largest Hospital in Manhattan and greater NYC. He will be serving as a solution architect and providing recommendations for system improvements along with implementing agreed upon changes.
  
  Business Process Analyst
  Port of Long Beach Program
  October
  2015
  November
  2018
  Configured and deployed new and revised business process workflows within the Port's Primavera Unifier PMIS.
  Assisted with integration between existing systems and providing recommendations as necessary for process improvements and enhancements to the existing PMIS.
  Served as task lead, providing direction and quality assurance for work done by project team members including configuration, deployment, data integration reporting, user training, and documentation.
  
  PMIS Integrator
  MassPort Program
  June
  2008
  October
  2015
  Developed and implemented an information management strategy to align MPA with the best practices and modern systems of effective project delivery.
  Assisted with the development and implementation of the information management strategy which included strategic business processes, PMIS implementation, KPIs, reporting, and BI dashboards and systems integration. Mr. Cook is a business systems expert who is led the configuration and deployment of PMWeb, the new project management information system used by the Massachusetts Port Authority (Massport) for managing their capital construction program.
  
 </work>
</record>
<record>
 <name>
  John J Ciccarelli
 </name>
 <position>
  Project Manager
 </position>
 <education>
  Rutgers University
  MBA
  Real Estate
  
  University of Delaware
  BS
  Civil Engineering
  
 </education>
 <bio>
  Accomplished, well-rounded and versatile senior-level professional with more than 25 years of experience developing, selling, and delivering expert advisory and consulting services for public and private clients in a broad spectrum of industries and on complex business matters internationally. Broad skill set with extensive experience leading teams and collaborating to deliver successful results focused in the areas of project management, risk management, and dispute resolution combined with the ability to effectively synthesize strategy, plans and analyses and communicate with multiple internal and external stakeholders at all levels.

Highly analytical decision-maker and detail-oriented manager with strong organizational skills and experience directing multiple engagements simultaneously from initiation through close out, and able to work well under pressure to meet deadlines. Strategic thinker involved with executive level teams and initiatives with the ability to be hands-on. Proven people leader with emotional intelligence and history of recruiting, training and mentoring individuals, setting and inspiring personnel to achieve organizational and personal goals, and building cross-functional teams across disciplines. Business development skills to lead marketing, selling and closing opportunities and by demonstrating value added propositions. Industry experience: Construction; Real Estate (commercial and institutional buildings, hospitals, hotels); Power/Utility (fossil fuel, renewables cogeneration and nuclear); Infrastructure (wastewater treatment plants, transportation, roadways and bridges); Oil & Gas; Petrochemical/Chemical; Pharmaceutical/Life Sciences. Recognized by peers as an industry leader through numerous appointments to Boards of Directors and committee chair positions and for thought leadership demonstrated by frequent speaking engagements.


 </bio>
 <certificate>
  NY State Board Professional Engineers
  Professional Engineer
  
  American Association of Cost Engineers
  Project Scheduling Professional
  
 </certificate>
 <image>
  JohnCiccarelli.jpg
 </image>
 <expertise>
  Risk Management
  Project Advisory and Management
  Project Controls
  Negotiations
  Construction Management
 </expertise>
 <skills>
  Microsoft Suite
  Oracle Primavera
  Talented Multi-Tasker
  Microsoft Office
 </skills>
 <work>
  Senior Vice President
  Marsh & McLennan
  October
  2010
  Present
  
  Contributed 30% to Construction Consulting Services practice sales revenue, including $1.3 million in 2016 and $1.0 million in 2017.
  Designated as Northeast Zone leader and effectively managed corporate restructuring and relocation of practice.
  Directed expert dispute, risk management, and insurance claim analyses on significant international assignments for engineering and construction projects in the United States, Canada, Madagascar, Korea, and Trinidad and Tobago.
  Designated subject matter expert for Northeast Utility client and led preparation of $200 million insurance claim for reconstruction of gas transmission and distribution infrastructure.
  Directed project risk advisory consulting teams on more than $5 billion of projects that supported corporate suite decisions, merger and acquisition transactions, and accounting valuations for power plants, nuclear utilities, hotels, hospitals, mines, highways and bridges, and pharmaceutical facilities.
  
  Manager
  Deloitte Financial Advisory Services
  June
  2007
  October
  2010
  Grew Capital Projects Consulting practice by developing business and sales of $1.13, $1.33 and $1.13 million.
  Oversaw preparation of expert reports and resolved disputes favorably for clients on highway, higher education, oil & gas, wastewater treatment plant and nuclear facilities.
  Led multi-functional consulting team and developed procurement strategy, technical, operational and financial criteria, and contract documents for a Northeast city’s design/build/operate/maintain contract to implement a congestion pricing program.
  Oversaw governance assessment of a Southern Department of Transportation functions for project development, construction, maintenance, inspection, accounting, and information technology; recommendations were adopted to improve project delivery of an $8 billion annual capital program.
  Directed construction audits on more than $1 billion of projects that supported corporate suite decisions, including merger and acquisition transactions and accounting valuations for power plants, hotels, hospitals, mines, and highways and bridges.
  
  Managing Engineer
  EFAA
  February
  2005
  June
  2007
  Contributed to growth of the Construction Consulting practice in the New York City office by developing and executing marketing, sales, and hiring plans and directing staff on dispute and project advisory engagements.
  Developed and grew repeat business for performance and payment application reviews for financial institution owners of data center projects with more than $380 million of costs audited.
  Oversaw analysis of 41 schedules for recovery of costs on the Central Artery/Tunnel project in Boston.
  Directed expert analysis and preparation of $8.6 million claim on a highway project in Missouri which resulted in successful recovery of costs for contractor client.
  
  Senior Associate
  Nielsen-Wulster Group
  January
  1996
  February
  2005
  Promoted to Regional Manager for Northeast office to oversee day-to-day operations and grow office of professional experts.
  Testified regarding expert schedule and cost analysis resulting in successful resolution for the client on a $23 million disputed claim on a subway project.
  Directed expert dispute and risk management analyses on significant international assignments for engineering and construction projects in Angola, Argentina, Australia, Canada, Egypt, Hong Kong, Malaysia, Netherlands, Philippines, Saudi Arabia and Venezuela.
  Developed relational database and determined $46.5 million of work order costs for a nuclear power plant refueling outage which were successfully included in the utility’s rate base.
  
 </work>
</record>
<record>
 <name>
  Abhishek Singh Banyal
 </name>
 <position>
  Project Controls Specialist
 </position>
 <education>
  New Jersey Institute of Technology
  MSc
  Construction Management
  
  SRM University
  BS
  Civil Engineering
  
 </education>
 <bio>
  Abhishek Banyal is among Toll International LLC's key Project Controls Specialists and is one of their most promising candidate for this proposal. Abhishek Graduated from SRM University in 2014 and committed to Site-Based work for a Government Contractor for a period of two years before moving to the United States in 2016. He went on to complete his Graduate Degree in Construction Management from the New Jersey Institute of Technology in 2018; and as the best outgoing candidate, was awarded an Institutional Fellowship sponsored by a well-known Civil Engineering firm based in Morristown, NJ for his academic excellence.

Abhishek Banyal possesses an overall work experience of over 3 years and has accumulated a significant amount of site-based field-work during that time. He has been part of heavy engineering and infrastructure construction projects ranging from Hydro-Electric Power Generation in the Utilities Sector, to Roadways and Urban-Rail/Public-mass-transit enterprises in the transportation sector. His notable work experiences have placed him on both sides of the business, having worked in client/consulting as well as contracting agencies. His professional commitments have also netted him an assignment on an International, high-profile project based in the Asian market where he coordinated with professionals from India, England, South Korea, Taiwan and France.

Abhishek Banyal's particular expertise comes from his prior work experiences in maintaining Documentation, Proposal Writing, Contract Management, Estimating with CSI Master Format Specifications, Work-Breakdown-Structuring, Activity Timing / Logic, Activity Scheduling, Resource Allocation / Management, and Earned Value Analysis. His skills cover advanced knowledge of Microsoft Project Professional, and Oracle Primavera P6. Abhishek is also skilled in Autodesk software, having been an Autodesk Inc. endorsed, officially Licensed and web-published Professional since 2012.


 </bio>
 <certificate>
  Constr. Mgmt. Assoc. of America
  Construction Managemer In Training
  
 </certificate>
 <image>
  Abhishek.jpg
 </image>
 <expertise>
  CPM Scheduling
  Uniformat Estimating
  CAD
  CAE
 </expertise>
 <skills>
  Primavera P6
  ANSYS
  AutoCAD
  STAAD.Pro
  Project Professional
 </skills>
 <work>
  Project Controls Specialist
  Toll International LLC
  April
  2019
  Present
  
  Responsible for the company's outgoing proposals in response to published Requests for Proposals (RFPs) from the Port Authority of New York and New Jersey (PANYNJ)
  Represent the company, in maintenance of outward relations and interactions with partnering subcontractors as well as new prospects
  
  NJIT Fellow; Graduate Engineer
  Louis Berger Inc.
  June
  2018
  August
  2018
  Awarded the 2018 NJIT fellowship sponsored by the Berger charitable foundation
  Contributed to Project Monitoring by Inspection and Data Collection during blasting, mass-excavation, and tunnel boring operations on the Government of Maharashtra, Mumbai Metro Rail Corporation's Underground Line-3 Project
  Reviewed Schedules, Two-week-rolling Programs, Contractor Method Statements, Structural Engineering Drawings, Geo-technical Investigation Reports, Mechanical Engineering Drawings, Crane Load Charts and Data Records
  Witnessed the complete assembly, and Initial-drive of Surya-I -- a dual mode Tunnel Boring Machine procured from Robbins of Solon, Ohio; one of 17 overall TBMs committed to the project
  
  Site Engineer
  M/S Nirmal Rana
  March
  2012
  March
  2015
  On-site technical supervision, assistance & overall quality assurance with respect to roadwork and associated support structures such as drainage culverts, and retaining walls
  
  Engineering Intern
  Public Works Department
  June
  2013
  July
  2013
  Reviewed the design of an RCC bridge, manual and computer aided drafting as well as rain-waterharvesting regulations & practice in the state of Himachal Pradesh, India
  
  Engineering Intern
  National Hydroelectric Power Corporation
  May
  2004
  February
  2006
  Witnessed the execution and production phase of the NHPC's 520 MW, Parbati Hydroelectric Project - III
  With the bulk of the rock-fill type embankment dam, h/t race-tunnels, and powerhouse cavern nearing completion at the time, was introduced to tunnel-boring operations in fractured rock, underground construction, and the typical developmental progression of hydroelectric power projects
  
 </work>
</record>
<record>
 <name>
  Richard Lamanna
 </name>
 <position>
  Technology Specialist
 </position>
 <education>
  Western Connecticut State University
  BS
  Computer Science
  
 </education>
 <bio>
  Richard Lamanna leverages a background working in Information Technology where he developed expert-level skills managing and administering computer systems and databases, using analytical skills to solve complex problems, along with custom software development and user experience design. He is very skilled in systems architect with experience designing, configuring, and deploying project controls systems, information portals, and various database systems. He has served as technical lead on multiple projects, working for first hand on impactful designs for databases for companies like Boeing and IBM. Mr. Lamanna facilitates user interfaces by managing databases efficiently and without any technical difficulties. His expertise around Oracle Primavera software and other PMIS systems, such as E-Builder and Unifier, have been utilized in configuration and deployment projects, data migration efforts, and software assessments. He understands the technical side of configuration and development including the Software Development Life Cycle but also has a wealth of knowledge regarding the process optimization and excellent troubleshooting skills for performance issues. Additionally, he leverages expert knowledge of software for management of team collaboration, user acceptance testing, software documentation, and other languages such as SQL to optimize speed for user purposes.


 </bio>
 <certificate>
  Scrum.org
  Professional Scrum Master
  
 </certificate>
 <image>
  RichardLamanna.jpg
 </image>
 <expertise>
  IT Project Management
  Database Design
  Data Migration
  Data Integration
 </expertise>
 <skills>
  Oracle Primavera P6, CM
  E-Builder
  Micrsoft Office
  Java, C++
  Unifier
 </skills>
 <work>
  Senior Oracle Database Administrator
  Toll International LLC
  March
  2017
  Present
  
  Upgrading Primavera Release 7.0 to Release 16.2.0.0 on a Sun Solaris Release 5.8 environment.
  Migrate current Oracle environment 10.2.0.2 up to Oracle Release 12.1.0.2. Worked in all phases
  of migration and testing with the new releases of Oracle and Primavera.
  Set up database monitoring using OEM Version 12c
  
  Senior Database Administrator
  Datavil
  Arpil
  2011
  February
  2017
  Oracle 11g/12c, RAC Architecture, Configuration, and Administration.
  Excellent troubleshooting skills for performance issues.
  Oracle DataGuard across multi-data oracle standby instances
  
  Senior Oracle DBA
  BM Global Business
  June
  2009
  March
  2011
  Oracle database quarterly patching.
  Oracle Exadata and Oracle Data Guard Broker.
  SQL Tuning using Oracle SQL Tuning Advisor.
  
 </work>
</record>
<record>
 <name>
  Nure M. Aiza Bezares
 </name>
 <position>
  Principal-In-Charge
 </position>
 <education>
 </education>
 <bio>
  
 </bio>
 <certificate>
  American Association of Cost Engineers
  Project Scheduling Professional
  
  Design Build Institute
  Design Build Institute America
  
 </certificate>
 <image>
  
 </image>
 <expertise>
 </expertise>
 <skills>
 </skills>
 <work>
  Principal Consultant
  Department of Design and Construction
  April
  2017
  Present
  
  A $1.7 M of consulting services a year for the South East Queens Infrastructure Upgrade Program.
  This project consisted of IT data visualization, project management information systems, scheduling and cost engineering
  Managed the creation and expansion of resilient and sustainable infrastructure projects that will protect New York City against extreme weather emergencies and reduce green gas emissions.
  
  Principal Construction Scheduler
  Task 97 ORT Art and Architectural Enhancements
  February
  2017
  December
  2017
  Served as Toll Principal Consultant to HDR Program Management contract under sub-consulting agreement for the Art and Architectural Enhancements Program at 12 different tunnel and bridge locations.
  
  Principal-Consultant
  New York City Department of Environmental Protection
  May
  2017
  Present
  
  Serves as Principal-In-Charge for Toll rendered services delivered to NYDEP's Bureau of Engineering Design and Construction
  Responsible for the development and roll out of the BEDC manual and Training to DEP staff and third-party consultants
  
  Principal-Consultant
  Governor's Office of Storm Recovery
  March
  2016
  Present
  
  Serves as Toll Principal Consultant under sub-consulting agreement for engineering services agreement.
  Facilitates engineering workshops and present narrative reports of the resulting study.
  
  Principal-Consultant
  MTA New York City Transit (NYCT)
  October
  2010
  Present
  
  Served as Principal-In-Charge assisting the Deputy Vice President of Project Controls to deliver technical and management support under a $9 Million Indefinite Quantity/Indefinite Delivery services contract to support NYCT capital program management cost estimating, scheduling and contract to close out units.
  Provided specification writing services for the Modernization of Signal Systems at Several Interlockings throughout the NYCT system.
  Assembled summary reports containing key performance indicators for the director and chief.
  Advised construction manager and lead director during negotiations and change order administration.
  Served as Principal Consultant on $134 Million Design-Build Contract for Enhanced Stations Initiative (ESI).
  
  Senior Project Manager
  New York City School Construction Authority
  January
  2008
  Present
  
  Serves as Senior Project Manager in the delivery of Toll's $6 Million worth of comprehensive professional, technical and management support consulting services.
  
 </work>
</record>
<record>
 <name>
  Nure M. Aiza Bezares
 </name>
 <position>
  Principal-In-Charge
 </position>
 <education>
  MIT
  MS
  IT Construction Management
  
  Northwestern University
  MS
  Project Management
  
 </education>
 <bio>
  Nure Miguel Aiza Bezares is the CEO and President of Toll International and serves as Principal-In-Charge on Port Authority contracts. He is a self starting Consultant with excellent oral and written communication skills and possesses nearly 25 years of extensive work experiences leading public work projects. Nure Aiza is an independent adviser in project / program management, scheduling, cost-estimating, value engineering and capital construction planning. He has developed and delivered professional training programs in the utilization of project management and information technology tools relating to complex capital construction programs and design-build mega-projects. He is an expert at synthesizing project management and program management support knowledge and transferring it to both client staff and third-party consultants.

Mr. Aiza has a strong understanding of The Port Authority project management manual and project controls systems, which enables him to successfully lead project management services and program management support services. In addition to his Port Authority experience, he has been responsible for leading work assignments with several public clients including MTA-NYCT's Signal, Train Control and Communications Contracts, the MTA's Design-Build Enhanced Station Initiative, as well as their Capital Construction Program, the Triborough Bridge and Tunnel Authority's Fast Tolling Program, the NYC Department of Environmental Protection, New York City School Construction Authority and New York City Department of Design and Construction. He achieved the PSP certificate, designated DBIA and is active at the Association for the Advancement of Cost Engineering (AACE) and Design Build Institute of America (DBIA). His formal education includes degrees from MIT, Stanford University, Dartmouth College, New York University and Northwestern University. Mr. Aiza was recently recognized as an Emergent Industry Leader by the US Small Business Administration.


 </bio>
 <certificate>
  American Association of Cost Engineers
  Planning Scheduling Professional
  
  Design Build Professional
  Design Build Institute America
  
 </certificate>
 <image>
  Nure.jpg
 </image>
 <expertise>
  IT Project Management
  IT Contract Management
  Critical Path Method Scheduling
  Value Engineering
  Estimating
 </expertise>
 <skills>
  PMIS
  CMIS
  Oracle Primavera P3, P6
  Autodesk AutoCAD
  Microsoft Office
  Sage Estimating
 </skills>
 <work>
  
  Toll International
  
  2005
  Present
  
  
  
  Judlau Contracting
  
  2009
  
  2009
  
  
  The Louis Berger Group
  
  2008
  
  2008
  
  
  STV Construction
  
  2007
  
  2007
  
  
  PMA Consultants
  
  2002
  
  2007
  
 </work>
</record>
<record>
 <name>
  John R. Knoke
 </name>
 <position>
  Technical Director
 </position>
 <education>
  Central Michigan University
  MBA
  Project Management
  
  University of Toledo
  BS
  Industrial Management
  
 </education>
 <bio>
  John R. Knoke currently serves as Technical Director, Quality Manager, and as a Scheduling/Claims Expert with Toll International. He works on site at the New York City School Construction Authority for their Oracle Primavera upgrade services from PPM R7.0 to R16.2. He possesses more than 45 years of experience in project and contract management, cost and schedule control, and estimating for major infrastructure, environmental, architectural, transportation, and power projects with a cumulative value of more than $25 billion. His proven expertise in Directing and Executing the development and application of construction and project management information systems - those involving CPM based activity Scheduling, Project Cost-Estimating, cost/schedule management, the analysis of contractor requests for equitable adjustments, change-order and delay-claims analysis, and scheduling implementation establishes him as a leading Scheduling candidate from Toll International for this Proposal.

John R. Knoke is more than proficient with Primavera, database, and application development software. He has been an active user of Primavera planning and scheduling products since 1984, including recent P6 versions, PPM and EPPM 16. He is an accomplished technical director and has served as a developer of business process data integrations, associating P6 with external data sources. John has been officially certified as an Oracle Primavera trainer since 2003 and has conducted formalized training nationwide since that time.

His prior experience includes serving in increasingly responsible roles as lead area electrical field engineer, cost and scheduling engineer, project planner, resident engineer, and project/construction manager with various entities within the Bechtel Group working on projects within the continental United States and more impressively in the Middle East.


 </bio>
 <certificate>
  OH State Board of Professional Engineers
  Professional Engineer
  
  Project Management Institute
  Project Management Professional
  
 </certificate>
 <image>
  john.jpg
 </image>
 <expertise>
  Systems Design & Architecture
  Critical Path Method Scheduling
  Value Engineering
  Contract Management
  Estimating
  Project Management
 </expertise>
 <skills>
  Oracle Primavera P6, CM
  RS Means
  HCSS HeavyBid
  Microsoft Office
  Sage Estimating
 </skills>
 <work>
  
  Toll International LLC
  
  2016
  Present
  
  
  
  PMA Consultants
  
  1987
  
  2016
  
  
  Bechtel Group
  
  1971
  
  1987
  
 </work>
</record>
<record>
 <name>
  John R. Knoke
 </name>
 <position>
  Technical Director
 </position>
 <education>
 </education>
 <bio>
  
 </bio>
 <certificate>
  OH State Board of Professional Engineers
  Professional Engineer
  
  Project Management Institute
  Project Management Professional
  
 </certificate>
 <image>
  
 </image>
 <expertise>
 </expertise>
 <skills>
 </skills>
 <work>
  Director, Staffing
  New York School Construction Authority
  April
  2017
  Present
  
  Customer/Corporate coordination for the determination of requirements and to provide project management / controls / capital systems analyses, development, and training.
  Technical guidance for the upgrade analysis of Oracle Primavera Project Manager P6 solutions. Reviews of software interfaces relating to Primavera Project Manager (PPM). Directing developers during the analysis of the existing and future Primavera P6 data structures. Directing the analysis of P6 implementation documents and Oracle scripts.
  Guidance to the Project Manager and report writers with technical tasks during the identification, quantification and mitigation of Upgrade Risks. Guidance of efforts on custom software upgrades. Evaluation of applicable industry standards and provision of guidance during software development, database restructuring, network mapping, windows server implementation, security, mobility devices, cloud and HTML5 applications. Provides guidance and technical support for project initiation, planning, analysis, design & development.
  
  Principal Scheduler
  Port of Long Beach, CA
  
  
  
  
  Cost and schedule specialist assigned to support a $175 million Harry Tracy WTP upgrade. Monitor contractor’s progress, forecast completion dates, and provided recommendations for schedule enhancements.
  
  Principal Consultant
  City of San Francisco
  
  
  
  
  Cost and schedule specialist assigned to support a $175 million Harry Tracy WTP upgrade. Monitor contractor’s progress, forecast completion dates, and provided recommendations for schedule enhancements.
  
  Principal Consultant
  Port Authority of New York & New Jersey
  
  
  
  
  Reviewed and evaluated project controls programs within the authority's Engineering Department. Based on the evaluations, developed a comprehensive analysis of project management processes and a set of written technical recommendations for improvements. Concurrently, developed a set of schedule data review and reporting tools for the overall World Trade Center program schedule, and produced and presented a series of reporting tools for the overall World Trade Center program schedule, and produced and presented a series of reports for the authority's chief engineer.
  
 </work>
</record>
<record>
 <name>
  Ben Schulz
 </name>
 <position>
  Management Application Director
 </position>
 <education>
  Utah State University
  BS
  Information Systems
  
 </education>
 <bio>
  Ben possesses over 20 years worth of work experience in the development, customization and implementation of construction industry project and program management applications. This, paired with his knowledge of cost engineering, schedule management, and project risk management controls has enabled him to perform project management and estimating services in numerous industries.

He has experiences working as Project Manager, Implementation Specialist, as Data Analyst with P6, Contract Management, and BI Publishing and other report designing software. Ben is a Documentation Specialist experienced in the direct development of several user guides and training manuals. He has been the Technical Project Manager for Oracle Primavera P6 16.2 and Contract Management CM13/CM14 Upgrades for one of our key clients. He is experienced and knowledgeable in business analysis and the development of user requirements. He is also experienced with the Software Development Life Cycle Model. He has personal experience with CM14, Business Intelligence Publisher and with Primavera Contract Manager databases.

He is currently assigned as a Report Writer for Toll's work at the NYC School Construction Authority's PPM Upgrade project. There, he is diligently rewriting and updating Primavera Contract Management reports which are heavily utilized by the project management group. Ben possesses a keen awareness of process and procedure and is meticulous in providing users with desired automation in achieving their business objectives.


 </bio>
 <certificate>
  Project Management Institute
  Project Management Professional
  
 </certificate>
 <image>
  Ben.jpg
 </image>
 <expertise>
  Construction Management
  Contract Books Automation
  Contract Management
  Law Review Integration
  CPM based Scheduling
 </expertise>
 <skills>
  Oracle Primavera P6, CM
  Microsoft Office
  Microsoft Project
  MySQL
 </skills>
 <work>
  Senior Consultant
  Toll International LLC
  June
  2016
  Present
  
  Designs data visualization and a contract book automation system to assist in the delivery of capital construction programs for NYDDC
  Upgraded reporting automation in the SCA's Primavera Contract Manager
  
  Implementation Manager
  Chicago Public Schools
  March
  2014
  June
  2016
  Established Primavera Contract Manager construction documentation system for Chicago Public Schools
  Developed CM custom documents and procedures to automate project practices developed by CPS
  Developed WBS cost coding structure within project
  Designed procedures for change management, tracking & invoicing
  Automated reports for integration of agency policies and procedures into engineering contracts
  
  Implementation Consultant
  Burn & McDonnell
  October
  2000
  October
  2014
  Established a project's Primavera Contract Manager construction documentation system
  Developed a unique costing structure in CM to track costs instantaneously and on-demand
  Developed WBS cost coding structure within the project
  Designed procedures for change management, tracking and invoicing, environmental reporting, real estate location, tracking, purchasing, reselling
  Established specific logs to track key issues including crew tracking, public relations, and local/regional permitting
  Prepared monthly auditing reports
  
  Consultant
  Peak Construction Co.
  January
  2008
  July
  2010
  Responsible for implementation and design of Primavera Contract Manager software
  Created custom forms and reports in Infomaker and trained the users on how to use the tool
  
 </work>
</record>
<record>
 <name>
  Richard Onochie
 </name>
 <position>
  Senior Project Manager
 </position>
 <education>
  Howard University
  ME
  Civil Engineering
  
  University of Benin
  BE
  Civil Engineering
  
 </education>
 <bio>
  Richard Onochie is a thoroughly capable and experienced Construction Manager with an admirable & demonstrated history of working on complex highway and transportation engineering projects in the State of California. He is extremely skilled in Project & Construction Management, having worked on several high profile projects with Caltrans and other notable public agencies.

Richard Onochie has a technical and fundamental academic background in Civil Engineering which is enhanced by his Master's Degree in the same discipline. He acquired these qualifications in the early 1990s and joined Caltrans in committing himself to public sector work in the State of California. After more than 20 years of working with Caltrans, Richard switched to pursue a more lucrative career in the Private sector in 2014. He has worked in the capacity of Construction Managment Consulting with some prominent names active in the Private Sector market in the State of California.

Richard has a prior performance record of working in the capacity of contract administration and is also experienced in claims analyses, as well as the negotiation of contract changes. Richard has also been part of several design/build and similarly unconventional projects. Richard's body of work also includes the California High-Speed Rail Project and his work contributions to the WMATA's (Washington-Metropolitan Area Transit Authority) Station Rehabilitation Program.


 </bio>
 <certificate>
  California Board of Professional Engineers
  Professional Engineer
  
 </certificate>
 <image>
  RichardOnochie.jpg
 </image>
 <expertise>
  Project Management
  Critical Path Method Scheduling
  Value Engineering
  Budget Estimating
  Cost Control
 </expertise>
 <skills>
  Oracle Primavera P6, CM
  Microsoft Office
  Autodesk AutoCAD
 </skills>
 <work>
  Senior Construction Manager
  
  June
  2018
  Present
  
  Responsible for Construction Management on transportation projects
  Enforces plans, provides quality assurance, and provides change management
  Coordinates meetings and communications with stakeholders
  
  Principal Construction Manager
  Arcadis US
  October
  2017
  April
  2018
  Construction Manager assigned with the California High Speed Rail
  Responsible for construction oversight and project controls
  Worked with the design/build team to ensure proper delivery of the project
  Monitored quality, budget and issues
  
  Construction Engineering Consultant
  TEC Management Consultants
  February
  2017
  Present
  
  Contract administration on the Design/Build freeway corridor improvement project in Riverside County, California
  Monitored contractor's operations for compliance with contract
  Resolved issues, monitored safety, attended meetings, coordinated different agencies and functions
  Responsible for utility relocation and drainage
  
  Area Manager, Construction
  California Department of Transportation
  January
  1998
  May
  2014
  Construction Chief on several complex highway projects
  Supervised Resident Engineers and Construction Inspectors
  Participated in claims resolution and negotiated settlements
  Responsible for Partnering program in the District
  Provided training and interpretation of specifications
  Adequately staffed active projects and moved staff as and when required
  
  Resident Engineer
  California Department of Transportation
  January
  1994
  January
  1998
  Contract administration on several highway projects
  Responsible for proper payments to contractors
  Processed claims and reviewed submittals
  Prepared and processed change orders
  Coordinated across the several offices involved in ongoing projects
  Prepared claims reports and attended arbitration meetings
  
 </work>
</record>
<record>
 <name>
  Paris Y. Zhang
 </name>
 <position>
  Project Manager
 </position>
 <education>
  University of Hawaii
  MS
  Civil Engineering
  
  Jinzhou Institute of Technology
  BS
  Civil Engineering
  
 </education>
 <bio>
  Paris Zhang is a seasoned Civil Engineering Design and Construction Engineer with a truly outstanding professional experience and an excellent customer service record. After being educated in the United States at the University of Hawaii he readied himself to leverage his composite skills in Civil Engineering related disciplines to benefit various projects. Paris is equally at easy and adept at working with Private as well as Public Sector clients including both State and Federal Agencies. He is professionally Licensed both in the State of Hawaii and New York and has a an overall work experience of over 18 years.

Paris Zhang's portfolio of professional contributions to Civil Engineering and Construction Projects for public and federal agencies includes work accomplished for the US Department of Interior, the US Army, The State of Hawaii, and The Port Authority of NY & NJ. Furthermore, based on the strength of his qualifications and his professional profile, Paris Zhang has been working on overseas assignments with the US Army Corps of Engineers as well.

Paris Zhang brings not only a his outstanding repertoire of positions held, projects and accomplishments achieved with governmental agencies; but also the highly objective impartial professional rigour that is commanded to attain them. We believe that Paris Zhang is one of the most qualified and the most highly accomplished candidates on our proposal and that we not only recommend but endorse his candidacy with pleasure and with confidence.


 </bio>
 <certificate>
  Hawaii Board of Prof. Engineers
  Professional Engineer
  
 </certificate>
 <image>
  Paris.jpg
 </image>
 <expertise>
  Project Management
  Critical Path Method Scheduling
  Value Engineering
  Estimating
  Contract Management
 </expertise>
 <skills>
  Oracle Primavera P3, P6
  Autodesk AutoCAD
  Microsoft Office
  Sage Estimating (Timberline)
 </skills>
 <work>
  Interdisciplinary Supervisor
  
  February
  2018
  Present
  
  Supervisor-in-charge of a $50 million Design-build Project for the US department of Navy located in Bahrain
  Supervisory-in-charge for the US Navy for another $4 million Construction Project in Bahrain
  
  Project Manager
  Jacobs / CH2M
  July
  2017
  February
  2018
  Project manager for US Postal Office projects in the Tri-State area
  Designed for  infrastructure, land development, and repair / alteration
  Reviewed design drawings, data collection devices, assessments
  Provided scope and rough order of magnitude for repairs and condition indices
  Performed energy audits to identify energy conservation scopes
  
  Civil Engineer
  US Department of Interior
  April
  2016
  June
  2017
  Provided Civil Engineering expertise to perform and direct design, construction, operations, and maintenance of park facilities
  Managed the preparation of planning & construction documents, specifications, cost estimates, and for advertised or negotiated procurements
  Conducted and supervises physical inventories of roads, trails, building, utilities, signs and other structures
  
  Construction Engineer
  The Port Authority of New York & New Jersey
  September
  2014
  April
  2016
  Provided Engineering serviced to monitor contractor adherence to plans, and specifications
  Investigated construction problems and determined the need for extra work
  Prepared reports and forecasts
  Inspected construction methods, schedules, material, and equipment requirements
  Provided justification, cost estimate and approve quantities of work in place for payments
  
  Principal-Consultant
  MTA New York City Transit
  October
  2010
  Present
  
  Planned, coordinated, organized, directed, and controlled variety of engineering and architectural services for State of Hawaii
  Handled end-to-end processes to facilitate quality control, contracting, construction management, and cost control for State Agencies
  Directed and approved planning/design logistics with Operation Department
  Coordinated with vendors and contractors to complete construction projects
  Prepared and reviewed technical memorandums, reports, drawings, specifications, as well as miscellaneous contract documents and deliverables
  Proactively managed changes within project scopes, identify issues and contingency plans
  
 </work>
</record>
<record>
 <name>
  Nicholas Chaya
 </name>
 <position>
  Cost Estimator
 </position>
 <education>
  Rhode Island School of Design
  MS
  Landscape Architecture
  
  The State University of New Jersey
  BS
  Landscape Architecture
  
 </education>
 <bio>
  Nicholas Chaya leverages a background working in Project Controls where he developed expert-level skills such as Change Order Review and Approval, RFI Review and Approval, Contract Management, Construction Standards Enforcement, Safety Standards Enforcement, Cost Estimation, Project Documentation, and Archiving. He has over 8 years of experience designing, configuring, and deploying project controls systems. He has served as Project Manager and Assistant Project Manager at the New York City Department of Environmental Protection. There he worked on multiple projects, working on a $2.7 Million Pedestrian Infrastructure Construction project, a $1.9 Million Green Infrastructure Construction project, and a  $2.8 Million Green Infrastructure Construction project. He also helped on a large-scale project for the city of New York: a $120 Million Hurricane Sandy Disaster Relief Job Project. His expertise with state organizations is also complemented with his 10 years of experience in Adobe Creative Suite, documentation, and  Microsoft Office Suite (10+ years),  and over 5 years of Contract Management, Project Management, and PM.

Nicholas graduated from Rhode Island School of Design with a Master's of Science in Landscape Architecture and received his Bachelor's of Science in Landscape Architecture at The State University of New Jersey.


 </bio>
 <certificate>
  Micrsoft
  Micrsoft Specialist
  
 </certificate>
 <image>
  NicholasChaya.jpg
 </image>
 <expertise>
  Change Order Review and Approval
  Contract Management
  Cost Estimation
  RFI Review and Approval
 </expertise>
 <skills>
  SketchUp
  CRM
  Adobe Creative Suite
  Microsoft Project
 </skills>
 <work>
  Project Manager
  Department of Environmental Protection
  July
  2018
  Present
  
  Overseeing Contract X092-508M from project start to project closeout in accordance with contract requirements, construction standards and contract budget.
  Overseeing Contract BG-117M from project start to project closeout in accordance with contract requirements, construction standards and contract budget.
  Closing out contract CNYG-512M, verifying quantities and work performed prior to final project sign off.
  Reviewing and resolving Request For Information submissions.
  Verifying material and document submissions for conformance with construction standards and performance specifications outlined in project contract books.
  Attending monthly project progress meetings with city officials, state officials and private consultants, providing updates and projections on completing critical project milestones.
  
  Assistant Project Manager
  Department of Environmental Protection
  July
  2017
  July
  2018
  Oversaw a Job Order Contract as part of the Build It Back, documented project progress and communicated tasks to field inspectors and assigned construction personnel.
  Reviewed and processed change orders for additional, justified construction work and payment.
  Reviewed and approved invoices submitted for payment.
  Enforced construction methods and health and safety standards as outlined in architectural drawings and protocols established by Build It Back.
  Prepared and updated project data utilized by Housing Recovery Operations (HRO) management in progress reports delivered to the New York City Office of the Mayor.
  Attended HRO production meetings, provided detailed progress updates and proposed strategies for increased efficiency.
  Coordinated efforts from participating private companies and city agencies in the completion of all support documentation, allowing for final sign off with the New York City Department of Buildings.
  
  Contract Manager
  Hill International
  April
  2015
  July
  2017
  Documented project progress as part of the Build It Back program, communicated tasks to field inspectors and expedited project execution and closeout in accordance with program standards.
  Documented and redesigned damaged sidewalks and right-of-ways across New York City in accordance with New York City Department of Parks and Recreation and Americans with Disabilities Act standards for the Trees and Sidewalks Program.
  Managed Street Trees Contract RG115M, directed all field work to be in conformance with New York City Department of Parks and Recreation standards.
  
  Project Manager
  Community Design Collaborative
  December
  2011
  April
  2015
  Developed presentations, recommendations, phasing strategies and preliminary cost estimates for the schematic design phase of projects.
  Coordinated team member tasks and ensured delivery of materials outlined in scope.
  Lead constructive dialogues with community organizations and the Philadelphia Water Department at meetings critical to project progress and approval.
  
 </work>
</record>
